<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>live on Sounding</title>
    <link>https://sounding.com/categories/live/</link>
    <description>Recent content in live on Sounding</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sun, 08 Sep 2019 05:12:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://sounding.com/categories/live/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Meander Sonor Ode</title>
      <link>https://sounding.com/2019/09/07/meander-sonor-ode/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 08 Sep 2019 05:12:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://sounding.com/2019/09/07/meander-sonor-ode/</guid>
      <description>(a listening deeply gift from the urban inside)
A speaker faced down the bench
where we sat, directly
adjacent to the Duet. Their aging laptops looping maybe scooping
the sound from their devices,
strung and hung in air plus wired,
synth sound supple and rounded
towards their combined long-tone sculpting. As the bench began to resonate,
this pool of glacial tones clustering
and extended found the grains
of smooth planked architecture,</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>LA Phil graces Cage’s Europeras 1 &amp; 2</title>
      <link>https://sounding.com/2018/11/14/la-phil-graces-cages-europeras-1-2/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 15 Nov 2018 06:46:48 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://sounding.com/2018/11/14/la-phil-graces-cages-europeras-1-2/</guid>
      <description>John Cage liked to borrow. Whether in musical style or approach to theatre, the materials themselves are often not his. Musical scores evolved into graphic iconography or instruction governed by brackets of time and/or duration. Written pieces were amalgamations, mesostics “written through” other authors’ work, or more “cut-up” style constructions of various texts.
It applied to his philosophies, too. He is known to take bits and pieces of Eastern practice and weave their concepts into his worldview and compositional process.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Fullerton Art Walk Menagerie</title>
      <link>https://sounding.com/2012/04/08/fullerton-art-walk-menagerie/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 09 Apr 2012 01:00:57 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://sounding.com/2012/04/08/fullerton-art-walk-menagerie/</guid>
      <description>Here’s my own collection of aural glass animals for you to enjoy… a mix of groovy and beaty dreamscapes (3:38 @ 256K cbr mp3), recorded live for the Fullerton Art Walk on Friday (April 6), accompanying tattoo artist Jon Kelly (known for Olde Tyme Tattoo) as he applies his latest in biomechanical fashion.
=== e d i t ===
…by the way a vinyl mix…
 </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>120 Hours For John Cage</title>
      <link>https://sounding.com/2012/02/14/120-hours-for-john-cage/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 14 Feb 2012 22:55:58 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://sounding.com/2012/02/14/120-hours-for-john-cage/</guid>
      <description>As you may or may not know, 2012 is the Centennial of John Cage’s birth, and among its many celebrants (including myself, details to come…) is “transmission arts” collective Free103point9, who work in conjunction with WGXC 90.7-FM in upstate New York to present works specifically designed for air-borne electro-magnetic transmission – Radio, that is.
As you also may or may not know, John Cage wrote an abundance of pieces that called for either radios as instruments or as the listening medium (i.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>got my NAMM pass ready…</title>
      <link>https://sounding.com/2012/01/18/got-my-namm-pass-ready/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 19 Jan 2012 04:54:50 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://sounding.com/2012/01/18/got-my-namm-pass-ready/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>