<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>listening on Sounding</title>
    <link>https://sounding.com/categories/listening/</link>
    <description>Recent content in listening on Sounding</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sun, 17 May 2020 22:40:20 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://sounding.com/categories/listening/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Anti-Bias of Listening Deeply</title>
      <link>https://sounding.com/2020/05/17/anti-bias-of-listening-deeply/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 17 May 2020 22:40:20 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://sounding.com/2020/05/17/anti-bias-of-listening-deeply/</guid>
      <description>Getting around cognitive biases (like “hindsight is 20/20” or a confirmation you expect) is akin to Listening Deeply. I don’t mean paying more attention gives better insight. I mean what matters is the entirety of your sonic awareness.

There is a composer / meditative approach to sound pioneered by Pauline Oliveros called Deep Listening. I have practiced it, all too briefly with her, but mostly with others taught by her.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Meander Sonor Ode</title>
      <link>https://sounding.com/2019/09/07/meander-sonor-ode/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 08 Sep 2019 05:12:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://sounding.com/2019/09/07/meander-sonor-ode/</guid>
      <description>(a listening deeply gift from the urban inside)
A speaker faced down the bench
where we sat, directly
adjacent to the Duet. Their aging laptops looping maybe scooping
the sound from their devices,
strung and hung in air plus wired,
synth sound supple and rounded
towards their combined long-tone sculpting. As the bench began to resonate,
this pool of glacial tones clustering
and extended found the grains
of smooth planked architecture,</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Music for WorkCats</title>
      <link>https://sounding.com/2019/08/28/music-for-workcats/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 28 Aug 2019 22:17:02 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://sounding.com/2019/08/28/music-for-workcats/</guid>
      <description>I have a few Slacks (as in chats, not pants) with #music and #jams channels where I feel obligated to post music I find good. I love sharing music. It’s why I got involved and loved my years on WUVT and WMUC DJ’ing, why I have always had a side-‘job’ as a DJ, why I made mixtapes in high school and recordings of my sets to share.
This was going to be a tweet thread but turned into something longer.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>MusiCirTechUs</title>
      <link>https://sounding.com/2019/03/21/musicirtechus/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 22 Mar 2019 02:00:23 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://sounding.com/2019/03/21/musicirtechus/</guid>
      <description>Plenty of people who work in technology are musicians. Plenty of humans are musicians, and all of us are listening, even those who cannot hear. In my travels through datacenters and software, I have come across musicians like myself who have not only done double-duty with their computer science and creative lives but also relate and interweave them. If they’re like me, they cannot break them apart. There are hundreds, if not thousands, of us.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Living 4’33”</title>
      <link>https://sounding.com/2019/01/19/living-433/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 19 Jan 2019 08:10:42 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://sounding.com/2019/01/19/living-433/</guid>
      <description>I haven’t experienced Mute’s STUMM433 release yet, it’s not due out until May. The proceeds from its sale go to charities, so that’s a big huge plus for it already. Pulling big names like Depeche Mode and Moby will hopefully make for good sales.
This is also not the first time 4’33” has been “recorded” for the purpose of a record release and not as part of a live performance. Frank Zappa has done it, Pauline Oliveros and the Deep Listening Band plus others, and some even got sued for it.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>So You Want 10 Albums?</title>
      <link>https://sounding.com/2019/01/01/so-you-want-10-albums/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 02 Jan 2019 05:01:29 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://sounding.com/2019/01/01/so-you-want-10-albums/</guid>
      <description>Ok Bob. You asked for it. With one caveat.
In no particular order, post 10 of your favorite albums, one per day, which made an impact on you. Post cover, no explanation, nominate someone each day to do the challenge.  I think these games are fascinating windows into peoples’ aesthetic, but because of FB’s sorting and selection criteria, I see maybe TWO of a particular friend’s ten-albums-once-per-day series. So, if I am taking the time to compile, I want to make sure you see them all.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Now Playing: Need it on Vinyl!</title>
      <link>https://sounding.com/2012/07/17/now-playing-need-it-on-vinyl/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 17 Jul 2012 14:34:06 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://sounding.com/2012/07/17/now-playing-need-it-on-vinyl/</guid>
      <description>– SCSI-9 ::: Metamorphosis –
– Extrawelt ::: In Aufruhr –
– Cristian Vogel ::: The Inertials –
– Forward Strategy Group ::: Labour Division –</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Now Playing</title>
      <link>https://sounding.com/2012/05/29/now-playing-3/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 29 May 2012 14:57:44 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://sounding.com/2012/05/29/now-playing-3/</guid>
      <description>– Peter Dundov ::: Ideas from the Pond –
– Squarepusher ::: Ufabulum –
– Fluxion ::: Traces EP 2/3 –
– Clark ::: Iradelphic –
– Actress ::: R.I.P. –</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Now Playing: New-to-me Edition</title>
      <link>https://sounding.com/2012/04/23/now-playing-new-to-me-edition/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 23 Apr 2012 16:43:23 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://sounding.com/2012/04/23/now-playing-new-to-me-edition/</guid>
      <description>– Orbital ::: In Sides –
– Dalglish ::: Benacah Drann Deachd –
– Aus ::: Lang –
– Tycho ::: The Science of Patterns –
– Various Artists ::: Elektronische Musik – Interkontinental –</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Fullerton Art Walk Menagerie</title>
      <link>https://sounding.com/2012/04/08/fullerton-art-walk-menagerie/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 09 Apr 2012 01:00:57 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://sounding.com/2012/04/08/fullerton-art-walk-menagerie/</guid>
      <description>Here’s my own collection of aural glass animals for you to enjoy… a mix of groovy and beaty dreamscapes (3:38 @ 256K cbr mp3), recorded live for the Fullerton Art Walk on Friday (April 6), accompanying tattoo artist Jon Kelly (known for Olde Tyme Tattoo) as he applies his latest in biomechanical fashion.
=== e d i t ===
…by the way a vinyl mix…
 </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Now Playing</title>
      <link>https://sounding.com/2012/03/14/now-playing-2/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 14 Mar 2012 22:19:57 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://sounding.com/2012/03/14/now-playing-2/</guid>
      <description>– Farben ::: Farben EP –
– Burnt Friedman ::: Bokoboko –
– Susumu Yokota ::: Dreamer –
– John Tejada &amp;amp; Justin Maxwell ::: Patch Adams / Thundaar the Modularian –
– Dalglish ::: Benacah Drann Deachd –
 </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Now Playing (M Edition!)</title>
      <link>https://sounding.com/2012/03/01/now-playing-m-edition/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 01 Mar 2012 15:59:14 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://sounding.com/2012/03/01/now-playing-m-edition/</guid>
      <description>– Martin Schulte ::: Treasure –
– Modula Green ::: Shellground –
– Minilogue ::: Let Life Dance Through You Remixes –
– Margaret Dygas ::: Margaret Dygas –
– Mouse on Mars ::: Parastrophics –</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Now Playing</title>
      <link>https://sounding.com/2012/02/17/now-playing/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 17 Feb 2012 15:55:29 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://sounding.com/2012/02/17/now-playing/</guid>
      <description>– Lackluster ::: The Invisible Spanish Inquisition –
– Steve Martin &amp;amp; The Steep Canyon Rangers ::: Rare Bird Alert –
– Marcus Fischer ::: Collected Dust –
– Woob ::: Paradigm Flux –
– Stimming ::: Cheesecake –</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Listening in 2011</title>
      <link>https://sounding.com/2012/01/11/listening-in-2011/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 11 Jan 2012 08:29:03 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://sounding.com/2012/01/11/listening-in-2011/</guid>
      <description>Three years ago was the last time I did any kind of “year’s review” of aural nourishment, and I sort of feel the need to do it again. Those 24 hours of music are worth revisiting, and the following may not even count as a “best of,” but it is some of the best music I’ve heard this year, and I listen to an awful lot. Maybe call it a “compendium”?</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Morton Subotnick Interviewed</title>
      <link>https://sounding.com/2011/11/29/morton-subotnick-interviewed/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 30 Nov 2011 01:08:05 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://sounding.com/2011/11/29/morton-subotnick-interviewed/</guid>
      <description>This is a great interview of an awesome figure in electronic music, done just recently (2011) in Madrid by the Red Bull Music Academy:
Listen to a free stream of Silver Apples of the Moon on last.fm.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Halloween Mixes by DJ Craque</title>
      <link>https://sounding.com/2010/11/04/halloween-mixes-by-dj-craque/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 05 Nov 2010 06:03:43 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://sounding.com/2010/11/04/halloween-mixes-by-dj-craque/</guid>
      <description>This past weekend we presented ourselves in regalia of the zombie, partying until the early single digits at my good friend Chad’s.
I have played music at his Halloween parties for as long as I’ve lived in California, down in Newport Beach as well as Fullerton. In 2010 the digital world has provided us with methods of being the DJ while joining the party; what follows are the set lists I prepared for the costume extravaganza at Chad’s, each on its separate ipod in different themed rooms:</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Miss Dinky up close</title>
      <link>https://sounding.com/2010/10/27/miss-dinky-up-close/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 28 Oct 2010 05:58:50 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://sounding.com/2010/10/27/miss-dinky-up-close/</guid>
      <description>The call burst across as I was sitting in the datacenter.
“LIHSTEN MAHN!” came the south London accent, and I could barely discern the tones of a minimal dubby Dirk Diggler broken beat track that I used to play all the time back on the turntables we had set up at the office… “IT’S TAHT ‘UN TRAC OO PLAHAY.”
When I walked into this place somewhere in SoHo, there were beams of light being reflected from everywhere around me.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Downtempo from the Studio</title>
      <link>https://sounding.com/2009/03/17/downtempo-from-the-studio/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 17 Mar 2009 21:45:15 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://sounding.com/2009/03/17/downtempo-from-the-studio/</guid>
      <description>I’ve set up a set in Soundcloud called “Downtempo Excursions” to post some sonic paintings created with free improvisation and minimal beats.
 Let me know what you think! These are sort of what I’d call “composting” of materials, kaleidoscopically tapestristic, experimentally structured.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>i don’t know how to do anything</title>
      <link>https://sounding.com/2009/03/02/i-dont-know-how-to-do-anything/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 02 Mar 2009 17:47:32 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://sounding.com/2009/03/02/i-dont-know-how-to-do-anything/</guid>
      <description>at times i get overwhelmed by possibilities. the details drag me down, and i lose sight of the path. what causes this?
for instance, what music do i choose to write? do i use electro-acoustic elements, or do i stick to raw sound design? do these ways of working always produce the same results, even though i cannot hear them? do i limit myself by focusing on a working method that could easily shift into tunnelvision?</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>New improvisations on SoundCloud</title>
      <link>https://sounding.com/2009/02/21/new-improvisations-on-soundcloud/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 21 Feb 2009 19:10:57 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://sounding.com/2009/02/21/new-improvisations-on-soundcloud/</guid>
      <description>Freely improvised one-takes. Instrumentation includes homebuilt instruments, sampled objects and looping hardware.
 This music sharing site is a great tool for posting various non-published tracks, as well as released stuff, and has a nice embeddable player and comment system. Really nice for being able to just slap some stuff up, I have one friend who has recently been doing the same with sessions on his new Serge Modular Creature, and another who posted “in progress” snapshots of a track he is working on.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>My best 24 hours of music in 2008</title>
      <link>https://sounding.com/2009/01/05/my-best-24-hours-of-music-in-2008/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 06 Jan 2009 05:54:52 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://sounding.com/2009/01/05/my-best-24-hours-of-music-in-2008/</guid>
      <description>I like to make myself feel as if I’m somehow close to the elusive community of electronic music. My problem, however, is that I am way too interested in multiple facets of music releases to pay attention in any style for very long. I seek out what really turns my ear, the gems of sound that are unique statements of purpose or individuality. Since I desire great pieces of listening, I spend time searching for it, which means I listen to a lot of not so great things too, and that goes double for netlabels.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Coming soon… Craque on Audiobulb</title>
      <link>https://sounding.com/2008/12/17/coming-soon-craque-on-audiobulb/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 18 Dec 2008 02:17:53 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://sounding.com/2008/12/17/coming-soon-craque-on-audiobulb/</guid>
      <description>So my new full-length album, Supple, will be released by Audiobulb in March of 2009. Ain’t that awesome! It’s a real honor to be joining in the ranks of Autistici, HeCanJog, Ultre, Calika, and so many others.
Months have gone by (actually, no, YEARS) where I have absorbed things, seen new parts of the world, learned new techniques, sought out what’s further; and this album evolved alongside me. The entire work has grown from single tracks and loose groupings to continuity and connection through thematic reverberation, it’s been fun and full of discovery.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>DataCent Failed HD Sound Library</title>
      <link>https://sounding.com/2008/11/17/datacent-failed-hd-sound-library/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 17 Nov 2008 21:23:19 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://sounding.com/2008/11/17/datacent-failed-hd-sound-library/</guid>
      <description>Check this out… DataCent, a data recovery company, has started a catalog of common sounds heard on failing hard drives, and it covers multiple vendors and situations where things can be heard going terribly wrong. Best of all, they give full permission to use the samples as long as you contact them about it.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Craque: Gamma out now on Test Tube</title>
      <link>https://sounding.com/2008/11/04/craque-gamma-out-now-on-test-tube/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 04 Nov 2008 19:37:23 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://sounding.com/2008/11/04/craque-gamma-out-now-on-test-tube/</guid>
      <description>October brought many exciting things for me, including not only a new job, but also a new album that I’m very excited about. The Test Tube netlabel is featuring this new release, called Gamma.
Six tracks, mostly beat-driven, of downtempo styled expressionism ripe with electro-acoustic improvisation; acousmatica for the brainwaves.
I was also honored to have Matt Mercer (of Microfilm) write up the release on Under the Lens, here’s an excerpt from the full article:</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The First Place I Heard Acid Jazz Was A Steven Jesse Bernstein Record</title>
      <link>https://sounding.com/2008/10/12/the-first-place-i-heard-acid-jazz-was-a-stephen-jesse-bernstein-record/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 12 Oct 2008 22:12:31 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://sounding.com/2008/10/12/the-first-place-i-heard-acid-jazz-was-a-stephen-jesse-bernstein-record/</guid>
      <description>It’s true.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Craque: “Tekuchesti” out now on Constanta</title>
      <link>https://sounding.com/2008/10/03/craque-tekuchesti-out-now-on-the-constanta-netlabel/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 03 Oct 2008 17:55:59 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://sounding.com/2008/10/03/craque-tekuchesti-out-now-on-the-constanta-netlabel/</guid>
      <description>I’m very happy to announce the release of a project I did this summer called Tekuchesti (a transliteration of текучести, which is a Russian word meaning “fluidity”), a piece in shuffle time for listeners and improvisers.
Download the entire work, and remember to listen on shuffle. Weird request you say? Read the liner notes below for more detail…
Please also visit the release page at Constanta and check out the other artists on this new boutique netlabel, which features some unique approaches to the microsound/glitch/experimental/drone genres; beauty through subtlety and simplicity.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Craque: “Trolling for Olives” now free download</title>
      <link>https://sounding.com/2008/10/02/craque-trolling-for-olives-now-free-download/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 03 Oct 2008 01:54:44 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://sounding.com/2008/10/02/craque-trolling-for-olives-now-free-download/</guid>
      <description>In 2001 the debut 12″ for Craque titled Trolling for Olives EP was released on Metatron Press, and now it’s available for free on last.fm.
All five tracks are both streamable and downloadable, I figured I’d do them all since the original is still available for purchase on vinyl and it’s got some dope tracks!
And I don’t know how many of my fans actually read this, but here’s the first hint that you can expect several new releases coming up in the coming months.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Bell Rung for Hiroshima</title>
      <link>https://sounding.com/2008/08/06/bell-rung-for-hiroshima/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 06 Aug 2008 17:26:28 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://sounding.com/2008/08/06/bell-rung-for-hiroshima/</guid>
      <description>Yesterday at 4:15PM (Pacific) I took a break from the chaos of networks and enjoyed a ceremonial oneness to honor the victims of Hiroshima in a gesture of world-wide harmony.
hiro1615080508shima starts about a minute before I rang in concert with many others across the globe for the Hiroshimia Peace Memorial Ceremony.
The recording was done in our garden walkway among our tropicals and succulents, you can hear the neighbor’s roof-top AC droning in the background, accompanied by our other neighbor’s dog.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The quake song</title>
      <link>https://sounding.com/2008/07/29/the-quake-song/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 30 Jul 2008 03:09:13 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://sounding.com/2008/07/29/the-quake-song/</guid>
      <description>Having moved to the LA area little over five years ago, it wasn’t until today that I experienced a significantly violent earthquake in our hometown of Fullerton – just across the freeway from the epicenter of the 5.4 quake in Chino Hills today.
I was talking on the phone in my studio for work, when suddenly it all started moving.
What’s interesting to me now is that though I remember the specific feeling of the earthquake, the adrenaline rush of anticipating when it will end, the cycles of disbelief and acceptance and small notions of what the edge of panic feels like… of all this, I remember the sounds the most.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>