<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>External on Sounding</title>
    <link>https://sounding.com/categories/external/</link>
    <description>Recent content in External on Sounding</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Tue, 14 Feb 2012 22:55:58 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://sounding.com/categories/external/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>120 Hours For John Cage</title>
      <link>https://sounding.com/2012/02/14/120-hours-for-john-cage/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 14 Feb 2012 22:55:58 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://sounding.com/2012/02/14/120-hours-for-john-cage/</guid>
      <description>As you may or may not know, 2012 is the Centennial of John Cage’s birth, and among its many celebrants (including myself, details to come…) is “transmission arts” collective Free103point9, who work in conjunction with WGXC 90.7-FM in upstate New York to present works specifically designed for air-borne electro-magnetic transmission – Radio, that is.
As you also may or may not know, John Cage wrote an abundance of pieces that called for either radios as instruments or as the listening medium (i.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Listening in 2011</title>
      <link>https://sounding.com/2012/01/11/listening-in-2011/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 11 Jan 2012 08:29:03 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://sounding.com/2012/01/11/listening-in-2011/</guid>
      <description>Three years ago was the last time I did any kind of “year’s review” of aural nourishment, and I sort of feel the need to do it again. Those 24 hours of music are worth revisiting, and the following may not even count as a “best of,” but it is some of the best music I’ve heard this year, and I listen to an awful lot. Maybe call it a “compendium”?</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Ubuweb posts Greenaway’s 4 American Composers</title>
      <link>https://sounding.com/2011/12/08/ubuweb-posts-greenaways-4-american-composers/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 08 Dec 2011 16:40:26 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://sounding.com/2011/12/08/ubuweb-posts-greenaways-4-american-composers/</guid>
      <description>Back in the mid 90’s before I ever got into techno music, I owned the original VHS copy of Peter Greenaway’s 1983 release 4merican Composers (natch, “Four American Composers”) and watched it constantly while in music school; I think I probably saw the Cage movie no less than 10 times.
As a honorable musicologist is want to do, I lent my copy out to a friend who had never heard of any of them, but then never got it back because of moving across the country.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Line6 ignoring Mac users?</title>
      <link>https://sounding.com/2011/12/06/line6-ignoring-mac-users/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 06 Dec 2011 22:38:38 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://sounding.com/2011/12/06/line6-ignoring-mac-users/</guid>
      <description>Someone showed me this incredibly awesome looking ‘DIY’ pedal being done by Line6 called the ToneCore DSP Developer’s Kit. At first I think, aaah what a cool platform for custom DSP pedal effects, what a nice little generic pedal with cool ways of creating my own DSP configurations… you can imagine the excitement, so unfortunately diffused by this paragraph:
 Will this platform be available on the Mac?
Probably not, sorry.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Morton Subotnick Interviewed</title>
      <link>https://sounding.com/2011/11/29/morton-subotnick-interviewed/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 30 Nov 2011 01:08:05 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://sounding.com/2011/11/29/morton-subotnick-interviewed/</guid>
      <description>This is a great interview of an awesome figure in electronic music, done just recently (2011) in Madrid by the Red Bull Music Academy:
Listen to a free stream of Silver Apples of the Moon on last.fm.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Matrix Mixering</title>
      <link>https://sounding.com/2011/04/03/matrix-mixering/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 03 Apr 2011 17:40:54 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://sounding.com/2011/04/03/matrix-mixering/</guid>
      <description>I’m building a 3×3 matrix mixer and have been scouring the Internet for examples and technical ideas. Even though a Google search can give you days of examples of opinions on which OpAmp to use at what stage, I’m more interested in the actual pedagogy of building the thing in the first place. So here are some of the better links I’ve uncovered that are useful for getting your head around the entire idea of designing a matrix mixer.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Doepfer DIY audio circuits</title>
      <link>https://sounding.com/2010/09/18/doepfer-diy-audio-circuits/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 18 Sep 2010 20:47:34 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://sounding.com/2010/09/18/doepfer-diy-audio-circuits/</guid>
      <description>Check out these great DIY schematics and tutorials for audio electronics published by Doepfer… found this while working on a passive mixer for Long Beach SoundWalk.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>My best 24 hours of music in 2008</title>
      <link>https://sounding.com/2009/01/05/my-best-24-hours-of-music-in-2008/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 06 Jan 2009 05:54:52 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://sounding.com/2009/01/05/my-best-24-hours-of-music-in-2008/</guid>
      <description>I like to make myself feel as if I’m somehow close to the elusive community of electronic music. My problem, however, is that I am way too interested in multiple facets of music releases to pay attention in any style for very long. I seek out what really turns my ear, the gems of sound that are unique statements of purpose or individuality. Since I desire great pieces of listening, I spend time searching for it, which means I listen to a lot of not so great things too, and that goes double for netlabels.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>DataCent Failed HD Sound Library</title>
      <link>https://sounding.com/2008/11/17/datacent-failed-hd-sound-library/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 17 Nov 2008 21:23:19 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://sounding.com/2008/11/17/datacent-failed-hd-sound-library/</guid>
      <description>Check this out… DataCent, a data recovery company, has started a catalog of common sounds heard on failing hard drives, and it covers multiple vendors and situations where things can be heard going terribly wrong. Best of all, they give full permission to use the samples as long as you contact them about it.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Craque: Gamma out now on Test Tube</title>
      <link>https://sounding.com/2008/11/04/craque-gamma-out-now-on-test-tube/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 04 Nov 2008 19:37:23 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://sounding.com/2008/11/04/craque-gamma-out-now-on-test-tube/</guid>
      <description>October brought many exciting things for me, including not only a new job, but also a new album that I’m very excited about. The Test Tube netlabel is featuring this new release, called Gamma.
Six tracks, mostly beat-driven, of downtempo styled expressionism ripe with electro-acoustic improvisation; acousmatica for the brainwaves.
I was also honored to have Matt Mercer (of Microfilm) write up the release on Under the Lens, here’s an excerpt from the full article:</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Infinite Jest Project @ .microsound</title>
      <link>https://sounding.com/2008/10/14/infinite-jest-project-microsound/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 14 Oct 2008 18:14:40 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://sounding.com/2008/10/14/infinite-jest-project-microsound/</guid>
      <description>The .microsound community recently embarked on a new project to honor the life of writer David Foster Wallace, known widely for his intelligently sprawling novel Infinite Jest.
Instructions were to take one of the films attributed to the protagonist’s father and create a soundtrack. I was attracted to the surrealism in the description of Baby Pictures of Famous Dictators and almost immediately had an image of what the film would be like.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Experimental Music Links</title>
      <link>https://sounding.com/2008/08/25/experimental-music-links/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 25 Aug 2008 23:07:01 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://sounding.com/2008/08/25/experimental-music-links/</guid>
      <description>I’m usually happening upon all kinds of things while I’m across the Internets for work or play, and I’ll document the more interesting and pertinent ones here on sounding.com.
I keep my own list of interesting Audio Hardware, as well as links to useful Audio Software, a lot of which centers around open source or DIY.
Check out Audio Culture for general experimental audio society.
Get Some is my list of “obtaining” art and sound across the Internet, both pay-sites and places you can get free stuff.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Nodal: Generative MIDI software</title>
      <link>https://sounding.com/2008/08/14/nodal-generative-midi-software/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 14 Aug 2008 17:20:37 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://sounding.com/2008/08/14/nodal-generative-midi-software/</guid>
      <description>There’s a new generative music package out now called Nodal, which uses an object oriented interface that gives composers control over every aspect of MIDI in a string-it-together sort of Max/PD style.
It will work with any MIDI capable synth, software or hardware, which means it works with most anything like Live, GarageBand or Logic as well as your outboard synths. My outboard synths with MIDI are long gone, and I do next to no work with software synths, but it does look interesting.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Getting into Circuit-Bending?</title>
      <link>https://sounding.com/2008/08/02/getting-into-circuit-bending/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 02 Aug 2008 18:00:56 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://sounding.com/2008/08/02/getting-into-circuit-bending/</guid>
      <description>Sound Art at Anti-Theory.com professes to be where “the art of circuit-bending was launched on the internet,” and it’s actually a nice resource for getting into avant-garde uses of musical toys.
In [how it works] a step-by-step example shows the simple circuit-bending process, and other topics go into things like tools and equipment and advanced things about electronics.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Erotus Records Kickoff Set</title>
      <link>https://sounding.com/2008/07/29/erotus-records-kickoff-set/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 29 Jul 2008 23:34:56 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://sounding.com/2008/07/29/erotus-records-kickoff-set/</guid>
      <description>Here’s a live set from the guys at Erotus (Blamstrain’s new label) celebrating its launch, featured in the Viides Uuden Musiikin Festivaali, or “Fifth Festival for New Music”, held in Kupittaanpuisto, Turku, Finland.
Download it to hear area, asketix, blamstrain, ercola, and mk10 (not necessarily in that order) throw down a continuous two and a half hour set of glitch-filled, sometimes psychedelic, always atmospheric minimal techno from 25 July in Finland.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Twisted Records now has downloads</title>
      <link>https://sounding.com/2008/07/26/twisted-records-now-has-downloads/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 26 Jul 2008 20:04:12 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://sounding.com/2008/07/26/twisted-records-now-has-downloads/</guid>
      <description>One of my favorite sources for anything psychedelic, Twisted Records has started an online store with digital downloads.
Traditionally this has been a “DJ’s label” selling mostly vinyl and CDs of primarily music meant to be spun at a party, but it’s interesting to see them offering things digitally.
It matches up a bit with the direction of some of the music Posford and friends make now, a lot less “fringey” I’d call it – more use of pop elements some might say – not any less worldly but a lot more accessible for the common ear.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>DIY photo-sensitive synth</title>
      <link>https://sounding.com/2008/07/08/diy-photo-sensitive-synth/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 08 Jul 2008 21:33:02 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://sounding.com/2008/07/08/diy-photo-sensitive-synth/</guid>
      <description>I’m excited to be waiting on the arrival of my new Bleep Labs ThingamaKIT.
Not unlike the simple improvising synth I’ve been working on with VCOs and 2-pole filters, this is a DIY version of their photo-sensitive thingamagoop, described on their website as simply:
“The Thingamagoops have oscillators just like any synth. On analog synths the oscillator that creates the actual tone you hear is called a VCO or voltage controlled oscillator.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>T Spigot is rearing its burroughsian head once again</title>
      <link>https://sounding.com/2008/05/14/t-spigot-is-rearing-its-burroughsian-head-once-again/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 14 May 2008 18:31:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://sounding.com/2008/05/14/t-spigot-is-rearing-its-burroughsian-head-once-again/</guid>
      <description>My favorite live downtempo band – T Spigot – is back in action this year, and to start it off they’re offering the limited edition first pressing of Experiments in the Hypnotic Production of Crime, available through paypal for a measly $5, so go get it!
The bonus is that this version of the album includes the remix of dubnbud which they did for the 12″ release of Trolling for Olives.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>