<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Music Tech on Sounding</title>
    <link>https://sounding.com/categories/music-tech/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Music Tech on Sounding</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 11 Sep 2019 20:39:41 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://sounding.com/categories/music-tech/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Musical City Techno</title>
      <link>https://sounding.com/2019/09/11/musical-city-techno/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 11 Sep 2019 20:39:41 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://sounding.com/2019/09/11/musical-city-techno/</guid>
      <description>Cicada, cricket, grasshopper, frog. However that particular indeterminate carpet of sound occurs, it is a permanent feature of the American South. I grew up in this soup, so hearing this familiar symphony again after nearly two decades of being away felt surreal and magical.
It is the sound that framed my stay in Nashville, Music City, for three mini-conferences all held at once at the Nossi College of Art: Music City Agile, Music City Code, and Music City Data.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Morton Subotnick Interviewed</title>
      <link>https://sounding.com/2011/11/29/morton-subotnick-interviewed/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 30 Nov 2011 01:08:05 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://sounding.com/2011/11/29/morton-subotnick-interviewed/</guid>
      <description>This is a great interview of an awesome figure in electronic music, done just recently (2011) in Madrid by the Red Bull Music Academy:
Listen to a free stream of Silver Apples of the Moon on last.fm.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Internetworking</title>
      <link>https://sounding.com/2010/11/16/internetworking/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 16 Nov 2010 17:01:41 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://sounding.com/2010/11/16/internetworking/</guid>
      <description>A lonely computer music lab, between practice and Early Music Ensemble rehearsal. Sitting at my workstation, the phosphor lines glow back in friendship, inviting the experience. On some other terminal across an expanse of ocean lay the eyes and hands of another typist. For one reason or another, connected to the same server, our consciousness met through ‘talk’ and the revelation hit me that this new network – in 1991 barely used by anyone but scientists and art geeks – not only passively gave us text with pictures, but also brought us together.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>A new improv tool is born</title>
      <link>https://sounding.com/2010/09/05/a-new-improv-tool-is-born/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 05 Sep 2010 20:53:37 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://sounding.com/2010/09/05/a-new-improv-tool-is-born/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>My synth project: complete!</title>
      <link>https://sounding.com/2009/03/11/my-synth-project-complete/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 12 Mar 2009 07:01:29 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://sounding.com/2009/03/11/my-synth-project-complete/</guid>
      <description>Here’s something I thought I’d never see myself do in my own lifetime: build a synthesizer from scratch.
Actually it’s a simple design: 2 555 timers in astable configuration producing square-waves. This means it’s a burst of sound every interval, pretty annoying and not very useful except for maybe starting earthquakes. So to give it a little flavor, I put a low-pass, 2-pole filter on the output of each oscillator, using a traditional operational amplifier.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>New improvisations on SoundCloud</title>
      <link>https://sounding.com/2009/02/21/new-improvisations-on-soundcloud/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 21 Feb 2009 19:10:57 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://sounding.com/2009/02/21/new-improvisations-on-soundcloud/</guid>
      <description>Freely improvised one-takes. Instrumentation includes homebuilt instruments, sampled objects and looping hardware.
 This music sharing site is a great tool for posting various non-published tracks, as well as released stuff, and has a nice embeddable player and comment system. Really nice for being able to just slap some stuff up, I have one friend who has recently been doing the same with sessions on his new Serge Modular Creature, and another who posted “in progress” snapshots of a track he is working on.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>DataCent Failed HD Sound Library</title>
      <link>https://sounding.com/2008/11/17/datacent-failed-hd-sound-library/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 17 Nov 2008 21:23:19 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://sounding.com/2008/11/17/datacent-failed-hd-sound-library/</guid>
      <description>Check this out… DataCent, a data recovery company, has started a catalog of common sounds heard on failing hard drives, and it covers multiple vendors and situations where things can be heard going terribly wrong. Best of all, they give full permission to use the samples as long as you contact them about it.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Updated Audio Software</title>
      <link>https://sounding.com/2008/10/10/updated-audio-software/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 10 Oct 2008 18:21:10 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://sounding.com/2008/10/10/updated-audio-software/</guid>
      <description>I’ve done some updates to the Audio Software page, including three new categories: “Looping and Performance”, “Free Players and Visualizers” and “Programming Languages”.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>SoundHack Delay Trio Released</title>
      <link>https://sounding.com/2008/09/03/soundhack-delay-trio-released/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 03 Sep 2008 22:17:24 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://sounding.com/2008/09/03/soundhack-delay-trio-released/</guid>
      <description>Tom Erbe is one of the members of the electronic music community whose work I highly respect. Not only is most of his software free, not only are they usable by any skill level, not only are they the most educational electronic music tools i’ve ever used… I could go on. But the end result is that they sound simple and great.
At long last Tom has released the SoundHack Delay Trio, the description of the algorithms is fantastic, from the announcement:</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>