<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>improvisation on Sounding</title>
    <link>https://sounding.com/tags/improvisation/</link>
    <description>Recent content in improvisation on Sounding</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sun, 17 May 2020 22:40:20 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://sounding.com/tags/improvisation/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Anti-Bias of Listening Deeply</title>
      <link>https://sounding.com/2020/05/17/anti-bias-of-listening-deeply/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 17 May 2020 22:40:20 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://sounding.com/2020/05/17/anti-bias-of-listening-deeply/</guid>
      <description>Getting around cognitive biases (like “hindsight is 20/20” or a confirmation you expect) is akin to Listening Deeply. I don’t mean paying more attention gives better insight. I mean what matters is the entirety of your sonic awareness.
  There is a composer / meditative approach to sound pioneered by Pauline Oliveros called Deep Listening. I have practiced it, all too briefly with her, but mostly with others taught by her.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Meander Sonor Ode</title>
      <link>https://sounding.com/2019/09/07/meander-sonor-ode/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 08 Sep 2019 05:12:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://sounding.com/2019/09/07/meander-sonor-ode/</guid>
      <description>(a listening deeply gift from the urban inside)
A speaker faced down the bench
where we sat, directly
adjacent to the Duet. Their aging laptops looping maybe scooping
the sound from their devices,
strung and hung in air plus wired,
synth sound supple and rounded
towards their combined long-tone sculpting. As the bench began to resonate,
this pool of glacial tones clustering
and extended found the grains
of smooth planked architecture,</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Musical Intuition meet Technology and Chaos</title>
      <link>https://sounding.com/2018/12/26/musical-intuition-meet-technology-and-chaos/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 27 Dec 2018 02:57:40 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://sounding.com/2018/12/26/musical-intuition-meet-technology-and-chaos/</guid>
      <description>Today I read through the InfoQ eMag on Chaos Engineering, and was struck by John Allspaw’s (@allspaw) contribution because it reminded me of something I jotted down on a sticky at my desk a few days ago:
 Intuition is valid because it is learned like jazz changes.  I’m pretty stubborn and refuse to accept that music is merely a hobby of mine. When people ask me if electronic music or singing is my “hobby”, I am wincing inside.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>SoundWalk 2011 is coming</title>
      <link>https://sounding.com/2011/08/31/soundwalk-2011-is-coming/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 31 Aug 2011 18:01:36 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://sounding.com/2011/08/31/soundwalk-2011-is-coming/</guid>
      <description>Just in case you missed it, SoundWalk Long Beach 2011 is just around the corner! Check out the newly posted set of mp3’s from last year’s event at craque.net (or download a zip file of flac files directly).
Here’s a couple of pix from last year’s event…
[][2]Craque performing at SoundWalk 2010 in Long Beach, CA [][3]Dave doubles as stagehand and soundmaker improvisor [][4]Later in the evening, up close with participants </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>New Instruments</title>
      <link>https://sounding.com/2010/08/06/new-instruments/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 07 Aug 2010 06:11:05 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://sounding.com/2010/08/06/new-instruments/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Downtempo from the Studio</title>
      <link>https://sounding.com/2009/03/17/downtempo-from-the-studio/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 17 Mar 2009 21:45:15 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://sounding.com/2009/03/17/downtempo-from-the-studio/</guid>
      <description>I’ve set up a set in Soundcloud called “Downtempo Excursions” to post some sonic paintings created with free improvisation and minimal beats.
 Let me know what you think! These are sort of what I’d call “composting” of materials, kaleidoscopically tapestristic, experimentally structured.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>New improvisations on SoundCloud</title>
      <link>https://sounding.com/2009/02/21/new-improvisations-on-soundcloud/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 21 Feb 2009 19:10:57 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://sounding.com/2009/02/21/new-improvisations-on-soundcloud/</guid>
      <description>Freely improvised one-takes. Instrumentation includes homebuilt instruments, sampled objects and looping hardware.
 This music sharing site is a great tool for posting various non-published tracks, as well as released stuff, and has a nice embeddable player and comment system. Really nice for being able to just slap some stuff up, I have one friend who has recently been doing the same with sessions on his new Serge Modular Creature, and another who posted “in progress” snapshots of a track he is working on.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Pull of the Unexplored</title>
      <link>https://sounding.com/2008/07/19/the-pull-of-the-unexplored/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 19 Jul 2008 20:08:08 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://sounding.com/2008/07/19/the-pull-of-the-unexplored/</guid>
      <description>Once aspect of creativity I haven’t quite discovered how to manage is the navigation of intuition.
It strikes me that some are better than others at accessing this elusive part of the imagination. As a visceral experience it’s unmistakable, but the pathways to obtaining that level of immersion are not so clear.
Inspiration strikes at the most incredulous opportunity; sometimes it’s like a pull, like gravitation towards a goal not seen, being drawn into a feeling that is indescribable beyond the need to create.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Metatron Press releases Gray Code on archive.org</title>
      <link>https://sounding.com/2008/04/17/metatron-press-releases-gray-code-on-archiveorg/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 17 Apr 2008 20:02:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://sounding.com/2008/04/17/metatron-press-releases-gray-code-on-archiveorg/</guid>
      <description>Metatron Press (the website is slightly outdated, but not necessarily incorrect) has started a netlabel archive, posting releases formerly available only on CDR, as well as more new stuff to come.
A quintet I played in for some time called Gray Code now has a live recording up, from the 2000 Philadelphia Fringe Festival.
The name of the group is taken from the structure we often used to improvise: “In performances using the Gray Code structure for five players, we proceed through all the possible combinations of members of the group, including the silence that starts and ends the performance, five solos, ten duets, ten trios, five quartets, and the single quintet involving all the players.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>New on CraqueCast: Amalgamation</title>
      <link>https://sounding.com/2008/01/09/new-on-craquecast-amalgamation/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 09 Jan 2008 21:17:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://sounding.com/2008/01/09/new-on-craquecast-amalgamation/</guid>
      <description>Starting off the new year with an archival live show: Amalgamation: Live at Smartbar, Chicago, 2002 is a set I did at SmartBar in March of 2002.
This is a set where I combined many influences, methods and directions together through a wide assortment of sampled objects, guitar playing, voices, and softsynths. It’s glitchy, ambient, dark, funky, beaty and bouncy all at the same time! A really nice listen with highly contrasting sections of sound and rhythm.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>