<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>composition on Sounding</title>
    <link>https://sounding.com/tags/composition/</link>
    <description>Recent content in composition on Sounding</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 30 Nov 2011 01:08:05 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://sounding.com/tags/composition/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Morton Subotnick Interviewed</title>
      <link>https://sounding.com/2011/11/29/morton-subotnick-interviewed/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 30 Nov 2011 01:08:05 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://sounding.com/2011/11/29/morton-subotnick-interviewed/</guid>
      <description>This is a great interview of an awesome figure in electronic music, done just recently (2011) in Madrid by the Red Bull Music Academy:
Listen to a free stream of Silver Apples of the Moon on last.fm.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Importance of Computer Silence</title>
      <link>https://sounding.com/2009/12/07/the-importance-of-computer-silence/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 07 Dec 2009 19:48:25 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://sounding.com/2009/12/07/the-importance-of-computer-silence/</guid>
      <description>It’s been a while since I’ve sincerely blogged, as I’ve been somewhat obscured by computing lately. You’d think with all these computers around me, I’d be blogging all the time; but what I really want is less of them around me so that it feels like something more special than just another thing I do on the computer.
For example, this weekend was my birthday weekend (born in 1971, for those counting), and it felt very good going on “computer silence” for two days after the Friday night party.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Nodal: Generative MIDI software</title>
      <link>https://sounding.com/2008/08/14/nodal-generative-midi-software/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 14 Aug 2008 17:20:37 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://sounding.com/2008/08/14/nodal-generative-midi-software/</guid>
      <description>There’s a new generative music package out now called Nodal, which uses an object oriented interface that gives composers control over every aspect of MIDI in a string-it-together sort of Max/PD style.
It will work with any MIDI capable synth, software or hardware, which means it works with most anything like Live, GarageBand or Logic as well as your outboard synths. My outboard synths with MIDI are long gone, and I do next to no work with software synths, but it does look interesting.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>