<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Sounding</title>
    <link>http://hpschd.xyz/</link>
    <description>Recent content on Sounding</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 12 Aug 2020 17:30:50 -0700</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="http://hpschd.xyz/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Music in Resilience</title>
      <link>http://hpschd.xyz/posts/music-in-resilience/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 12 Aug 2020 17:30:50 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://hpschd.xyz/posts/music-in-resilience/</guid>
      <description>You have probably heard the phrase “practice makes perfect”, but let’s take that thought up and out. It is really the experience of practice that is more interesting!
Consider a jazz band you’ve heard or seen live, or really any type of music where improvisation plays an important role. Great bands work together effortlessly, and when things go sideways or “wrong notes” are played, they quickly adapt to the changing conditions in order to keep the music going.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Anti-Bias of Listening Deeply</title>
      <link>http://hpschd.xyz/2020/05/17/anti-bias-of-listening-deeply/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 17 May 2020 22:40:20 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://hpschd.xyz/2020/05/17/anti-bias-of-listening-deeply/</guid>
      <description>Getting around cognitive biases (like “hindsight is 20/20” or a confirmation you expect) is akin to Listening Deeply. I don’t mean paying more attention gives better insight. I mean what matters is the entirety of your sonic awareness.
There is a composer / meditative approach to sound pioneered by Pauline Oliveros called Deep Listening. I have practiced it, all too briefly with her, but mostly with others taught by her. It is actually a discipline you can be certified to teach, which I am not, so here I refer to it as Listening Deeply.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Musical City Techno</title>
      <link>http://hpschd.xyz/2019/09/11/musical-city-techno/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 11 Sep 2019 20:39:41 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://hpschd.xyz/2019/09/11/musical-city-techno/</guid>
      <description>Cicada, cricket, grasshopper, frog. However that particular indeterminate carpet of sound occurs, it is a permanent feature of the American South. I grew up in this soup, so hearing this familiar symphony again after nearly two decades of being away felt surreal and magical.
It is the sound that framed my stay in Nashville, Music City, for three mini-conferences all held at once at the Nossi College of Art: Music City Agile, Music City Code, and Music City Data.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Meander Sonor Ode</title>
      <link>http://hpschd.xyz/2019/09/07/meander-sonor-ode/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 08 Sep 2019 05:12:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://hpschd.xyz/2019/09/07/meander-sonor-ode/</guid>
      <description>(a listening deeply gift from the urban inside)
(September, Nashville, 2019
Duet for Theremin and Lap Steel @ Proper Sake)</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Music for WorkCats</title>
      <link>http://hpschd.xyz/2019/08/28/music-for-workcats/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 28 Aug 2019 22:17:02 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://hpschd.xyz/2019/08/28/music-for-workcats/</guid>
      <description>I have a few Slacks (as in chats, not pants) with #music and #jams channels where I feel obligated to post music I find good. I love sharing music. It’s why I got involved and loved my years on WUVT and WMUC DJ’ing, why I have always had a side-‘job’ as a DJ, why I made mixtapes in high school and recordingsof my setsto share.
This was going to be a tweet thread but turned into something longer.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Meta Workshop Jam</title>
      <link>http://hpschd.xyz/2019/08/15/meta-workshop-jam/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 16 Aug 2019 03:00:13 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://hpschd.xyz/2019/08/15/meta-workshop-jam/</guid>
      <description>Walking late one afternoon after a day deep in Cognitive Systems and Resilience Engineeringworkshops, chatting with one of the eminent researchers in the field, the conversation circled around common ground in joint activity and sociotechnical systemssharing qualities with music ensembles. I remember agreeing how some uncategorizable thing exists on both sides as an outcome, where a result far greater than merely the sum of its parts occurs.
Music isn’t just the combination of the instruments, it’s the way in which humans push their operation forward through time both creating and adapting to the music and each other simultaneously.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Welcome to the Verified Machine</title>
      <link>http://hpschd.xyz/2019/04/11/welcome-to-the-verified-machine/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 12 Apr 2019 01:53:07 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://hpschd.xyz/2019/04/11/welcome-to-the-verified-machine/</guid>
      <description>Imagine for a moment that you’re a software team, pushing new versions into production. You’re working on multiple pieces independently, so as you make changes automation pulls it all together in orderly Continuous Integration. At the right moment, your team’s work is pushed and Continuous Delivery does the job. Five deploys a day? No problem. Y’all have written, collaborated, tested, and published your glorious stuff. Job well done!!!
Just kidding, you’re not done.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Pickles for Adam</title>
      <link>http://hpschd.xyz/2019/04/02/pickles-for-adam/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 03 Apr 2019 05:41:04 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://hpschd.xyz/2019/04/02/pickles-for-adam/</guid>
      <description>(on the _occasion_of our meeting and bridge crossing)
(March, New York City, 2019)</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>MusiCirTechUs</title>
      <link>http://hpschd.xyz/2019/03/21/musicirtechus/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 22 Mar 2019 02:00:23 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://hpschd.xyz/2019/03/21/musicirtechus/</guid>
      <description>Plenty of people who work in technology are musicians. Plenty of humans are musicians, and all of us are listening, even those who cannot hear. In my travels through datacenters and software, I have come across musicians like myself who have not only done double-duty with their computer science and creative lives but also relate and interweave them. If they’re like me, they cannot break them apart. There are hundreds, if not thousands, of us.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Weirdness of Experiment</title>
      <link>http://hpschd.xyz/2019/02/22/weirdness-of-experiment/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 23 Feb 2019 06:47:26 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://hpschd.xyz/2019/02/22/weirdness-of-experiment/</guid>
      <description>My job in ops has always been to keep things running. I never considered myself “working in software”, but have recently begun embracing the fact that I do. What I accomplish as an operationsand infrastructure engineer is part of the system, it isn’t dislocated from its composition.
Relatedly, I have been considering the nature of the experiment in Chaos Engineering. How continuous verification is becoming a crucial part of the complex systems we build because there really is no end.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>To Build or To Buy, That is the Contradiction.</title>
      <link>http://hpschd.xyz/2019/02/08/to-build-or-to-buy-contradiction/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 09 Feb 2019 00:46:51 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://hpschd.xyz/2019/02/08/to-build-or-to-buy-contradiction/</guid>
      <description>It’s dead simple. Focus on your team and product.
Yes! An easy tweetable answer! Except that it’s loaded with questions and assumptions. Instead, what I will talk about here are technology decisions. Those that really matter are about things that elevate your ability to build what you are building at the velocity you need.
In Operationsand SRE, we are not only tasked with evaluating and testing technologies, we are often requested (or sometimes instructed) to support the decisions others make.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Living 4’33”</title>
      <link>http://hpschd.xyz/2019/01/19/living-433/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 19 Jan 2019 08:10:42 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://hpschd.xyz/2019/01/19/living-433/</guid>
      <description>I haven’t experienced Mute’s STUMM433 release yet, it’s not due out until May. The proceeds from its sale go to charities, so that’s a big huge plus for it already. Pulling big names like Depeche Mode and Moby will hopefully make for good sales.
This is also not the first time 4’33” has been “recorded” for the purpose of a record release and not as part of a live performance. Frank Zappa has done it, Pauline Oliveros and the Deep Listening Band plus others, and some even got sued for it.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>So You Want 10 Albums?</title>
      <link>http://hpschd.xyz/2019/01/01/so-you-want-10-albums/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 02 Jan 2019 05:01:29 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://hpschd.xyz/2019/01/01/so-you-want-10-albums/</guid>
      <description>Ok Bob. You asked for it. With one caveat.
I think these games are fascinating windows into peoples’ aesthetic, but because of FB’s sorting and selection criteria, I see maybe TWO of a particular friend’s ten-albums-once-per-day series. So, if I am taking the time to compile, I want to make sure you see them all. Plus I’m all into the cross-platform sharing thing and doing this on my blog helps me spread the word of good music (and keeps me writing).</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Musical Intuition meet Technology and Chaos</title>
      <link>http://hpschd.xyz/2018/12/26/musical-intuition-meet-technology-and-chaos/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 27 Dec 2018 02:57:40 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://hpschd.xyz/2018/12/26/musical-intuition-meet-technology-and-chaos/</guid>
      <description>Today I read through the InfoQ eMag on Chaos Engineering, and was struck by John Allspaw’s (@allspaw) contribution because it reminded me of something I jotted down on a sticky at my desk a few days ago:
I’m pretty stubborn and refuse to accept that music is merely a hobby of mine. When people ask me if electronic music or singing is my “hobby”, I am wincing inside. So a question often on my mind is: how does the intuition I have when performing and composing music connect with the work I do as a technologist?</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Successful Tech Teams and the Superb DJ Set</title>
      <link>http://hpschd.xyz/2018/11/29/successful-tech-teams-and-the-superb-dj-set/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 30 Nov 2018 00:51:47 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://hpschd.xyz/2018/11/29/successful-tech-teams-and-the-superb-dj-set/</guid>
      <description>The term disc jockey was first coined in 1935, referring of course to the phonograph discs that had become popular for recorded music. Forty years and dozens of musical genre shifts later, the Technics SL-1200 direct drive paved the way for turntablists, still concerned with round artifacts of engraved sound, but doing more live manipulation than just selecting and playing tunes.
Since then, it has come to signify any presentation of recorded music mixed for a listening audience.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>LA Phil graces Cage’s Europeras 1 &amp; 2</title>
      <link>http://hpschd.xyz/2018/11/14/la-phil-graces-cages-europeras-1-2/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 15 Nov 2018 06:46:48 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://hpschd.xyz/2018/11/14/la-phil-graces-cages-europeras-1-2/</guid>
      <description>John Cage liked to borrow. Whether in musical style or approach to theatre, the materials themselves are often not his. Musical scores evolved into graphic iconography or instruction governed by brackets of time and/or duration. Written pieces were amalgamations, mesostics “written through” other authors’ work, or more “cut-up” style constructions of various texts.
It applied to his philosophies, too. He is known to take bits and pieces of Eastern practice and weave their concepts into his worldview and compositional process.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Shocking Before and After of Remoteness</title>
      <link>http://hpschd.xyz/2018/09/07/the-shocking-before-and-after-of-remoteness/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 07 Sep 2018 22:41:59 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://hpschd.xyz/2018/09/07/the-shocking-before-and-after-of-remoteness/</guid>
      <description>I was once employed at a startup whose attitude about remote workers had begun to retrograde to the point where even simple tolerance of the practice became a hot point. Leadership was known to stroll through offices and make comments about how they didn’t see butts in seats, even frequenting some facilities on early morning Fridays just to scoff at the emptiness of the expansive “open floor plans” where interruptions and distractions were kept at a maximum.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Caretakerlight</title>
      <link>http://hpschd.xyz/2018/08/04/caretakerlight/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 05 Aug 2018 02:57:33 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://hpschd.xyz/2018/08/04/caretakerlight/</guid>
      <description>The flowers sort of peeked
out of the tops of glasses.
They appeared to be in water,
surviving only because the tender kept them wet.
Their smell wafted across the corner of the bar,
hint of basil, tarragon,
a combo that seemed like the mix
of bergamot and chocolate.
The color of the green leaves
almost sparkled in the setting sun,
as beads of new water drifted
across the cool curve of the tiny hurricane glasses,</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>WUMC 1998: Mother of Invention</title>
      <link>http://hpschd.xyz/2018/05/26/wumc-1998-mother-of-invention/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 26 May 2018 23:40:35 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://hpschd.xyz/2018/05/26/wumc-1998-mother-of-invention/</guid>
      <description>I’ve been clearing out shelves and digging through old notebooks, and came across this steno pad from the summer of 1998, exactly 20 years ago. I lived in the northern suburbs of DC, worked as a graveyard shift unix system administrator at a datacenter company called Digex, and hosted a radio show for two years while I studied in graduate school as a vocal student and specialist in experimental vocal music and opera performance.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Remote Worker: A Primer</title>
      <link>http://hpschd.xyz/2018/03/23/remote_primer/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 23 Mar 2018 21:51:33 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://hpschd.xyz/2018/03/23/remote_primer/</guid>
      <description>I am the nerd who annoyed you as a roommate because I always had the phone line busy dialing into BBSes when you were pounding cheap beer to “jump up jump up and get down” in the living room, while I searched Usenet for pirated software and other nefarious files, loving the thrill of connecting to a different reality.I am the music major geek at a largely engineering-focussed university that sat for hours at the library VAX/VMS amber-toned terminal using raw telnet to log into MUDs and MOOs, attempting RPG challenges, having “virtual sex” and all other kinds of things, collaborating on tracks, partying together as a community IRL, and creating some of the strongest friendships I have today.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Now Playing: Need it on Vinyl!</title>
      <link>http://hpschd.xyz/2012/07/17/now-playing-need-it-on-vinyl/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 17 Jul 2012 14:34:06 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://hpschd.xyz/2012/07/17/now-playing-need-it-on-vinyl/</guid>
      <description>– SCSI-9 ::: Metamorphosis –
– Extrawelt ::: In Aufruhr –
– Cristian Vogel ::: The Inertials –
– Forward Strategy Group ::: Labour Division –</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Now Playing</title>
      <link>http://hpschd.xyz/2012/05/29/now-playing-3/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 29 May 2012 14:57:44 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://hpschd.xyz/2012/05/29/now-playing-3/</guid>
      <description>– Peter Dundov ::: Ideas from the Pond –
– Squarepusher ::: Ufabulum –
– Fluxion ::: Traces EP 2/3 –
– Clark ::: Iradelphic –
– Actress ::: R.I.P. –</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Now Playing: New-to-me Edition</title>
      <link>http://hpschd.xyz/2012/04/23/now-playing-new-to-me-edition/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 23 Apr 2012 16:43:23 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://hpschd.xyz/2012/04/23/now-playing-new-to-me-edition/</guid>
      <description>– Orbital ::: In Sides –
– Dalglish ::: Benacah Drann Deachd –
– Aus ::: Lang –
– Tycho ::: The Science of Patterns –
– Various Artists ::: Elektronische Musik – Interkontinental –</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>DIY Audio: UNPLUGGED</title>
      <link>http://hpschd.xyz/2012/04/11/diy-audio-unplugged/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 12 Apr 2012 00:36:58 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://hpschd.xyz/2012/04/11/diy-audio-unplugged/</guid>
      <description>Probably around five years ago now, while much further in the depths of a thrice-laid-off financial hole the technology industry bestowed upon me, I became fixated with actually building my own electronic instruments. Ensuing the expertise to make music that way, I departed into the wide unknown universe of DIY audio.
The first time I encountered a small, personal modular synthesizer was during a long gallery installation and collaborative work by Achim Wollscheidin Chicago (I also happened to have given him a ride to where he was going his first night there, and had rich conversations for the short time we were all together).</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Fullerton Art Walk Menagerie</title>
      <link>http://hpschd.xyz/2012/04/08/fullerton-art-walk-menagerie/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 09 Apr 2012 01:00:57 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://hpschd.xyz/2012/04/08/fullerton-art-walk-menagerie/</guid>
      <description>Here’s my own collection of aural glass animals for you to enjoy… a mix of groovy and beaty dreamscapes (3:38 @ 256K cbr mp3), recorded live for the Fullerton Art Walk on Friday (April 6), accompanying tattoo artist Jon Kelly (known for Olde Tyme Tattoo) as he applies his latest in biomechanical fashion.
=== e d i t ===
…by the way a vinyl mix…
 </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Now Playing</title>
      <link>http://hpschd.xyz/2012/03/14/now-playing-2/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 14 Mar 2012 22:19:57 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://hpschd.xyz/2012/03/14/now-playing-2/</guid>
      <description>– Farben ::: Farben EP –
– Burnt Friedman ::: Bokoboko –
– Susumu Yokota ::: Dreamer –
– John Tejada &amp;amp; Justin Maxwell ::: Patch Adams / Thundaar the Modularian –
– Dalglish ::: Benacah Drann Deachd –
 </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Proll Toys Mini Organ</title>
      <link>http://hpschd.xyz/2012/03/02/proll-toys-mini-organ/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 02 Mar 2012 20:13:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://hpschd.xyz/2012/03/02/proll-toys-mini-organ/</guid>
      <description>We own this D battery operated “mini organ” that has a real blower inside and some kind of reed system… I haven’t taken it apart yet to see, and somewhat afraid of breaking it, but it works and sounds really cool!</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Now Playing (M Edition!)</title>
      <link>http://hpschd.xyz/2012/03/01/now-playing-m-edition/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 01 Mar 2012 15:59:14 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://hpschd.xyz/2012/03/01/now-playing-m-edition/</guid>
      <description>– Martin Schulte ::: Treasure –
– Modula Green ::: Shellground –
– Minilogue ::: Let Life Dance Through You Remixes –
– Margaret Dygas ::: Margaret Dygas –
– Mouse on Mars ::: Parastrophics –</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Now Playing</title>
      <link>http://hpschd.xyz/2012/02/17/now-playing/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 17 Feb 2012 15:55:29 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://hpschd.xyz/2012/02/17/now-playing/</guid>
      <description>– Lackluster ::: The Invisible Spanish Inquisition –
– Steve Martin &amp;amp; The Steep Canyon Rangers ::: Rare Bird Alert –
– Marcus Fischer ::: Collected Dust –
– Woob ::: Paradigm Flux –
– Stimming ::: Cheesecake –</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>120 Hours For John Cage</title>
      <link>http://hpschd.xyz/2012/02/14/120-hours-for-john-cage/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 14 Feb 2012 22:55:58 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://hpschd.xyz/2012/02/14/120-hours-for-john-cage/</guid>
      <description>As you may or may not know, 2012 is the Centennial of John Cage’s birth, and among its many celebrants (including myself, details to come…) is “transmission arts” collective Free103point9, who work in conjunction with WGXC 90.7-FM in upstate New York to present works specifically designed for air-borne electro-magnetic transmission – Radio, that is.
As you also may or may not know, John Cage wrote an abundance of pieces that called for either radios as instruments or as the listening medium (i.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>dave smith arpeggiator madness!</title>
      <link>http://hpschd.xyz/2012/01/22/dave-smith-arpeggiator-madness/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 23 Jan 2012 00:11:03 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://hpschd.xyz/2012/01/22/dave-smith-arpeggiator-madness/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>metasonix tubey modules</title>
      <link>http://hpschd.xyz/2012/01/22/metasonix-tubey-modules/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 22 Jan 2012 23:46:18 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://hpschd.xyz/2012/01/22/metasonix-tubey-modules/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>built a fun patch at big city music</title>
      <link>http://hpschd.xyz/2012/01/22/built-a-fun-patch-at-big-city-music/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 22 Jan 2012 23:43:06 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://hpschd.xyz/2012/01/22/built-a-fun-patch-at-big-city-music/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>crazy console synthorgan</title>
      <link>http://hpschd.xyz/2012/01/22/crazy-console-synthorgan/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 22 Jan 2012 23:42:03 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://hpschd.xyz/2012/01/22/crazy-console-synthorgan/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>mellotrons old and new</title>
      <link>http://hpschd.xyz/2012/01/22/mellotrons-old-and-new/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 22 Jan 2012 23:05:44 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://hpschd.xyz/2012/01/22/mellotrons-old-and-new/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>DJ Vajra at Rane</title>
      <link>http://hpschd.xyz/2012/01/22/dj-vajra-at-rane/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 22 Jan 2012 22:06:24 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://hpschd.xyz/2012/01/22/dj-vajra-at-rane/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>futuristic devices at teenage engineering</title>
      <link>http://hpschd.xyz/2012/01/22/futuristic-devices-at-teenage-engineering/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 22 Jan 2012 21:32:07 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://hpschd.xyz/2012/01/22/futuristic-devices-at-teenage-engineering/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>last but not least: shwag</title>
      <link>http://hpschd.xyz/2012/01/19/last-but-not-least-shwag/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 20 Jan 2012 03:30:27 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://hpschd.xyz/2012/01/19/last-but-not-least-shwag/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>giant Analog Systems modular</title>
      <link>http://hpschd.xyz/2012/01/19/giant-analog-systems-modular/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 20 Jan 2012 01:50:48 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://hpschd.xyz/2012/01/19/giant-analog-systems-modular/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>another weird thing!</title>
      <link>http://hpschd.xyz/2012/01/19/another-weird-thing/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 20 Jan 2012 01:06:02 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://hpschd.xyz/2012/01/19/another-weird-thing/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>got to try this amazing bass flute</title>
      <link>http://hpschd.xyz/2012/01/19/got-to-try-this-amazing-bass-flute/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 20 Jan 2012 00:55:29 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://hpschd.xyz/2012/01/19/got-to-try-this-amazing-bass-flute/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>modular at Big City Music</title>
      <link>http://hpschd.xyz/2012/01/19/modular-at-big-city-music/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 20 Jan 2012 00:50:38 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://hpschd.xyz/2012/01/19/modular-at-big-city-music/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>custom pedal enclosures</title>
      <link>http://hpschd.xyz/2012/01/19/custom-pedal-enclosures/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 20 Jan 2012 00:47:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://hpschd.xyz/2012/01/19/custom-pedal-enclosures/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Tom Erbe’s Soundhack echo/pitchshifter</title>
      <link>http://hpschd.xyz/2012/01/19/tom-erbes-soundhack-echopitchshifter/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 19 Jan 2012 23:45:51 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://hpschd.xyz/2012/01/19/tom-erbes-soundhack-echopitchshifter/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>MakeNoise at AnalogueHaven</title>
      <link>http://hpschd.xyz/2012/01/19/makenoise-at-analoguehaven/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 19 Jan 2012 23:43:24 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://hpschd.xyz/2012/01/19/makenoise-at-analoguehaven/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>malekko modular</title>
      <link>http://hpschd.xyz/2012/01/19/malekko-modular/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 19 Jan 2012 22:24:38 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://hpschd.xyz/2012/01/19/malekko-modular/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>finally got to play a theremin!</title>
      <link>http://hpschd.xyz/2012/01/19/finally-got-to-play-a-theremin/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 19 Jan 2012 22:17:43 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://hpschd.xyz/2012/01/19/finally-got-to-play-a-theremin/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>thick bass madness from Moog</title>
      <link>http://hpschd.xyz/2012/01/19/thick-bass-madness-from-moog/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 19 Jan 2012 22:08:10 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://hpschd.xyz/2012/01/19/thick-bass-madness-from-moog/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>played on this one with Don Buchla himself</title>
      <link>http://hpschd.xyz/2012/01/19/played-on-this-one-with-don-buchla-himself/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 19 Jan 2012 21:12:20 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://hpschd.xyz/2012/01/19/played-on-this-one-with-don-buchla-himself/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>chromed monotribes</title>
      <link>http://hpschd.xyz/2012/01/19/chromed-monotribes/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 19 Jan 2012 20:59:11 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://hpschd.xyz/2012/01/19/chromed-monotribes/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>got my NAMM pass ready…</title>
      <link>http://hpschd.xyz/2012/01/18/got-my-namm-pass-ready/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 19 Jan 2012 04:54:50 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://hpschd.xyz/2012/01/18/got-my-namm-pass-ready/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Listening in 2011</title>
      <link>http://hpschd.xyz/2012/01/11/listening-in-2011/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 11 Jan 2012 08:29:03 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://hpschd.xyz/2012/01/11/listening-in-2011/</guid>
      <description>Three years ago was the last time I did any kind of “year’s review” of aural nourishment, and I sort of feel the need to do it again. Those 24 hours of music are worth revisiting, and the following may not even count as a “best of,” but it is some of the best music I’ve heard this year, and I listen to an awful lot. Maybe call it a “compendium”?</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Ubuweb posts Greenaway’s 4 American Composers</title>
      <link>http://hpschd.xyz/2011/12/08/ubuweb-posts-greenaways-4-american-composers/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 08 Dec 2011 16:40:26 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://hpschd.xyz/2011/12/08/ubuweb-posts-greenaways-4-american-composers/</guid>
      <description>Back in the mid 90’s before I ever got into techno music, I owned the original VHS copy of Peter Greenaway’s 1983 release 4merican Composers(natch, “Four American Composers”) and watched it constantly while in music school; I think I probably saw the Cage movie no less than 10 times.
As a honorable musicologist is want to do, I lent my copy out to a friend who had never heard of any of them, but then never got it back because of moving across the country.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Line6 ignoring Mac users?</title>
      <link>http://hpschd.xyz/2011/12/06/line6-ignoring-mac-users/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 06 Dec 2011 22:38:38 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://hpschd.xyz/2011/12/06/line6-ignoring-mac-users/</guid>
      <description>Someone showed me this incredibly awesome looking ‘DIY’ pedal being done by Line6 called the ToneCore DSP Developer’s Kit. At first I think, aaah what a cool platform for custom DSP pedal effects, what a nice little generic pedal with cool ways of creating my own DSP configurations… you can imagine the excitement, so unfortunately diffused by this paragraph:
 Will this platform be available on the Mac?
Probably not, sorry.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Morton Subotnick Interviewed</title>
      <link>http://hpschd.xyz/2011/11/29/morton-subotnick-interviewed/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 30 Nov 2011 01:08:05 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://hpschd.xyz/2011/11/29/morton-subotnick-interviewed/</guid>
      <description>This is a great interview of an awesome figure in electronic music, done just recently (2011) in Madrid by the Red Bull Music Academy:
Listen to a free stream of Silver Apples of the Moonon last.fm.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>SoundWalk 2011 is coming</title>
      <link>http://hpschd.xyz/2011/08/31/soundwalk-2011-is-coming/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 31 Aug 2011 18:01:36 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://hpschd.xyz/2011/08/31/soundwalk-2011-is-coming/</guid>
      <description>Just in case you missed it, SoundWalk Long Beach 2011 is just around the corner! Check out the newly posted set of mp3’s from last year’s event at craque.net(or download a zip file of flac files directly).
Here’s a couple of pix from last year’s event…</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>“Booglitchoo” Synth Prototype</title>
      <link>http://hpschd.xyz/2011/06/22/booglitchoo-synth-prototype/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 23 Jun 2011 06:52:13 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://hpschd.xyz/2011/06/22/booglitchoo-synth-prototype/</guid>
      <description>Here we go… I’ve optimized the way I’m using power, love the way the dual jfet opamps (TL082) sound, and have the mixing elements mostly decided.
To be done on this prototype:
 use either capacitor switching or a simple 4017 sequencer to change up the textural possibilities of the oscillator add switches to the voice modulator to allow for “skipping around” pitches instead of only up or down changes CV input  I went through quite a few opamps before finally deciding on the dual jfets, and now I really dig how they’re working with the complex waveform of the four NAND gates (NTE4093)… I use it first as a multipole low-pass filter to shape the sound of the chained oscillators.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Matrix Mixering</title>
      <link>http://hpschd.xyz/2011/04/03/matrix-mixering/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 03 Apr 2011 17:40:54 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://hpschd.xyz/2011/04/03/matrix-mixering/</guid>
      <description>I’m building a 3×3 matrix mixer and have been scouring the Internet for examples and technical ideas. Even though a Google search can give you days of examples of opinions on which OpAmp to use at what stage, I’m more interested in the actual pedagogy of building the thing in the first place. So here are some of the better links I’ve uncovered that are useful for getting your head around the entire idea of designing a matrix mixer.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>found objects: home-built percussion</title>
      <link>http://hpschd.xyz/2011/02/21/found-objects-home-built-percussion/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 21 Feb 2011 18:42:16 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://hpschd.xyz/2011/02/21/found-objects-home-built-percussion/</guid>
      <description>I like this collection of DIY and lo-fi instrumentsthat Rodrigo Constantzo has built, modded and incorporated into his percussion setup. Some great descriptions and ideas!</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>New on sounding: galleries!</title>
      <link>http://hpschd.xyz/2011/02/20/new-on-sounding-galleries/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 21 Feb 2011 04:48:44 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://hpschd.xyz/2011/02/20/new-on-sounding-galleries/</guid>
      <description>I’ve decided to pull all my sculpture and art photography here to a central gallery, and have a new page for my sculpturethat for now features most of the photos I have up on Deviant Art.
There’s a couple of new large works going, one that’s nearly complete and another just begun, photos to come soon!</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Internetworking</title>
      <link>http://hpschd.xyz/2010/11/16/internetworking/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 16 Nov 2010 17:01:41 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://hpschd.xyz/2010/11/16/internetworking/</guid>
      <description>A lonely computer music lab, between practice and Early Music Ensemble rehearsal. Sitting at my workstation, the phosphor lines glow back in friendship, inviting the experience. On some other terminal across an expanse of ocean lay the eyes and hands of another typist. For one reason or another, connected to the same server, our consciousness met through ‘talk’ and the revelation hit me that this new network – in 1991 barely used by anyone but scientists and art geeks – not only passively gave us text with pictures, but also brought us together.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Why am I silent?</title>
      <link>http://hpschd.xyz/2010/11/09/why-am-i-silent/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 10 Nov 2010 05:46:53 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://hpschd.xyz/2010/11/09/why-am-i-silent/</guid>
      <description>Incredibly, when I was a young boy I assumed everyone was supposed to know everything. It wasn’t until I was probably 30 that I realized things are meant to be learned and practiced, never known outright or assumed to be perfect.
But I spent a long time growing up thinking the opposite, that because I didn’t know something meant I couldn’t belong.
When I was thirteen, between finishing The Lord of the Rings and discovering Playboy, I locked onto a character in David Eddings’s The Belgariad; a wizardly type bloke who espoused silence and the ability to listen, leaving speech to those who knew not how to think.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Halloween Mixes by DJ Craque</title>
      <link>http://hpschd.xyz/2010/11/04/halloween-mixes-by-dj-craque/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 05 Nov 2010 06:03:43 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://hpschd.xyz/2010/11/04/halloween-mixes-by-dj-craque/</guid>
      <description>This past weekend we presented ourselves in regalia of the zombie, partying until the early single digits at my good friend Chad’s.
I have played music at his Halloween parties for as long as I’ve lived in California, down in Newport Beach as well as Fullerton. In 2010 the digital world has provided us with methods of being the DJ while joining the party; what follows are the set lists I prepared for the costume extravaganza at Chad’s, each on its separate ipod in different themed rooms:</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Miss Dinky up close</title>
      <link>http://hpschd.xyz/2010/10/27/miss-dinky-up-close/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 28 Oct 2010 05:58:50 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://hpschd.xyz/2010/10/27/miss-dinky-up-close/</guid>
      <description>The call burst across as I was sitting in the datacenter.
“LIHSTEN MAHN!” came the south London accent, and I could barely discern the tones of a minimal dubby Dirk Digglerbroken beat track that I used to play all the time back on the turntables we had set up at the office… “IT’S TAHT ‘UN TRAC OO PLAHAY.”
When I walked into this place somewhere in SoHo, there were beams of light being reflected from everywhere around me.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>creating obsessive beauty</title>
      <link>http://hpschd.xyz/2010/10/15/creating-obsessive-beauty/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 16 Oct 2010 03:58:59 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://hpschd.xyz/2010/10/15/creating-obsessive-beauty/</guid>
      <description>I happen to be a voracious reader. I would probably write more if I didn’t read so much. One thing I’ve noticed is the tendency to obsess on a single writer’s work: someone or something will turn me on to a specific author, I’ll read one of his or her works, and immediately want to read everything they’ve ever done. On occasion I accomplish this, but sometimes the task is simply too great.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>just some synth</title>
      <link>http://hpschd.xyz/2010/09/19/just-some-synth/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 20 Sep 2010 00:57:25 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://hpschd.xyz/2010/09/19/just-some-synth/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Doepfer DIY audio circuits</title>
      <link>http://hpschd.xyz/2010/09/18/doepfer-diy-audio-circuits/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 18 Sep 2010 20:47:34 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://hpschd.xyz/2010/09/18/doepfer-diy-audio-circuits/</guid>
      <description>Check out these great DIY schematics and tutorials for audio electronicspublished by Doepfer… found this while working on a passive mixer for Long Beach SoundWalk.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>A new improv tool is born</title>
      <link>http://hpschd.xyz/2010/09/05/a-new-improv-tool-is-born/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 05 Sep 2010 20:53:37 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://hpschd.xyz/2010/09/05/a-new-improv-tool-is-born/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>New Instruments</title>
      <link>http://hpschd.xyz/2010/08/06/new-instruments/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 07 Aug 2010 06:11:05 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://hpschd.xyz/2010/08/06/new-instruments/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How to Listen?</title>
      <link>http://hpschd.xyz/2010/05/06/how-to-listen/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 06 May 2010 15:27:08 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://hpschd.xyz/2010/05/06/how-to-listen/</guid>
      <description>So much music. Nowhere to begin. Everywhere is a beginning, none end.
Ever felt overwhelmed by the sheer numbers of works out there? I do all the time, daily in fact. I tend to find new listening by discovery through association, especially through publishers and artists that cross stylistic boundaries. Sometimes I feel like I have a certain knack to picking things out, almost to the extent it feels random, but in context it really never is.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Importance of Computer Silence</title>
      <link>http://hpschd.xyz/2009/12/07/the-importance-of-computer-silence/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 07 Dec 2009 19:48:25 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://hpschd.xyz/2009/12/07/the-importance-of-computer-silence/</guid>
      <description>It’s been a while since I’ve sincerely blogged, as I’ve been somewhat obscured by computing lately. You’d think with all these computers around me, I’d be blogging all the time; but what I really want is less of them around me so that it feels like something more special than just another thing I do on the computer.
For example, this weekend was my birthday weekend (born in 1971, for those counting), and it felt very good going on “computer silence” for two days after the Friday night party.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Appearing in variety…</title>
      <link>http://hpschd.xyz/2009/07/02/appearing-in-variety/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 03 Jul 2009 00:33:17 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://hpschd.xyz/2009/07/02/appearing-in-variety/</guid>
      <description>Audiobulb has released a free sampler of musicfrom eight artists on the label, including a track off Supple(see post below), subtly arranged and expertly mixed by label owner David Newman. Others included are: Jimmy Behan, Biosphere, Ultre, NQ, Mark Harris, Hans van Eck and He Can Jog. I’m honored to be among the talent in that lineup, and the music is just awesome.
Also recently, Xynthetic produced their Second Statement, a stunning cross-section of the artist roster that displays the wide variety to be had on the netlabel.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>“Supple” out now on Audiobulb</title>
      <link>http://hpschd.xyz/2009/04/07/supple-out-now-on-audiobulb/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 08 Apr 2009 02:45:35 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://hpschd.xyz/2009/04/07/supple-out-now-on-audiobulb/</guid>
      <description>Presenting: an electro-acoustic album of experimental sound sources and improvisations punctuated by iterative percussion, i.e. glitchy ambient slightly funky dance music. 😉
Supple is the way I’ve seen things come together over several years after moving to California, and owes some to dance forms that made this area of the country so important to electronic music development and culture. They are presented in a sort of story-form (I’ll blame my operatic tendencies for that), where endings and beginnings aren’t so easily discerned, and overall structure blends them in a sort of high-contrast, watercolor way… which I think is matched in visual form by gl0tch(check out the release pageto see different versions of the cover art morphing), giving it all this primordial evolutionary cybernetic aspect that I love, as if everything is a petri dish of mechanically chaotic musical questions.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Downtempo from the Studio</title>
      <link>http://hpschd.xyz/2009/03/17/downtempo-from-the-studio/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 17 Mar 2009 21:45:15 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://hpschd.xyz/2009/03/17/downtempo-from-the-studio/</guid>
      <description>I’ve set up a set in Soundcloud called “Downtempo Excursions” to post some sonic paintings created with free improvisation and minimal beats.
Let me know what you think! These are sort of what I’d call “composting” of materials, kaleidoscopically tapestristic, experimentally structured.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>My synth project: complete!</title>
      <link>http://hpschd.xyz/2009/03/11/my-synth-project-complete/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 12 Mar 2009 07:01:29 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://hpschd.xyz/2009/03/11/my-synth-project-complete/</guid>
      <description>Here’s something I thought I’d never see myself do in my own lifetime: build a synthesizer from scratch.
Actually it’s a simple design: 2 555 timers in astable configurationproducing square-waves. This means it’s a burst of sound every interval, pretty annoying and not very useful except for maybe starting earthquakes. So to give it a little flavor, I put a low-pass, 2-pole filter on the output of each oscillator, using a traditional operational amplifier.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>i don’t know how to do anything</title>
      <link>http://hpschd.xyz/2009/03/02/i-dont-know-how-to-do-anything/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 02 Mar 2009 17:47:32 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://hpschd.xyz/2009/03/02/i-dont-know-how-to-do-anything/</guid>
      <description>at times i get overwhelmed by possibilities. the details drag me down, and i lose sight of the path. what causes this?
for instance, what music do i choose to write? do i use electro-acoustic elements, or do i stick to raw sound design? do these ways of working always produce the same results, even though i cannot hear them? do i limit myself by focusing on a working method that could easily shift into tunnelvision?</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>New improvisations on SoundCloud</title>
      <link>http://hpschd.xyz/2009/02/21/new-improvisations-on-soundcloud/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 21 Feb 2009 19:10:57 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://hpschd.xyz/2009/02/21/new-improvisations-on-soundcloud/</guid>
      <description>Freely improvised one-takes. Instrumentation includes homebuilt instruments, sampled objects and looping hardware.
This music sharing site is a great tool for posting various non-published tracks, as well as released stuff, and has a nice embeddable player and comment system. Really nice for being able to just slap some stuff up, I have one friend who has recently been doing the same with sessions on his new Serge Modular Creature, and another who posted “in progress” snapshots of a track he is working on.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>My best 24 hours of music in 2008</title>
      <link>http://hpschd.xyz/2009/01/05/my-best-24-hours-of-music-in-2008/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 06 Jan 2009 05:54:52 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://hpschd.xyz/2009/01/05/my-best-24-hours-of-music-in-2008/</guid>
      <description>I like to make myself feel as if I’m somehow close to the elusive community of electronic music. My problem, however, is that I am way too interested in multiple facets of music releases to pay attention in any style for very long. I seek out what really turns my ear, the gems of sound that are unique statements of purpose or individuality. Since I desire great pieces of listening, I spend time searching for it, which means I listen to a lot of not so great things too, and that goes double for netlabels.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Coming soon… Craque on Audiobulb</title>
      <link>http://hpschd.xyz/2008/12/17/coming-soon-craque-on-audiobulb/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 18 Dec 2008 02:17:53 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://hpschd.xyz/2008/12/17/coming-soon-craque-on-audiobulb/</guid>
      <description>So my new full-length album, Supple, will be released by Audiobulbin March of 2009. Ain’t that awesome! It’s a real honor to be joining in the ranks of Autistici, HeCanJog, Ultre, Calika, and so many others.
Months have gone by (actually, no, YEARS) where I have absorbed things, seen new parts of the world, learned new techniques, sought out what’s further; and this album evolved alongside me. The entire work has grown from single tracks and loose groupings to continuity and connection through thematic reverberation, it’s been fun and full of discovery.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>DataCent Failed HD Sound Library</title>
      <link>http://hpschd.xyz/2008/11/17/datacent-failed-hd-sound-library/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 17 Nov 2008 21:23:19 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://hpschd.xyz/2008/11/17/datacent-failed-hd-sound-library/</guid>
      <description>Check this out… DataCent, a data recovery company, has started a catalog of common sounds heard on failing hard drives, and it covers multiple vendors and situations where things can be heard going terribly wrong. Best of all, they give full permission to use the samples as long as you contact them about it.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Craque: Gamma out now on Test Tube</title>
      <link>http://hpschd.xyz/2008/11/04/craque-gamma-out-now-on-test-tube/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 04 Nov 2008 19:37:23 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://hpschd.xyz/2008/11/04/craque-gamma-out-now-on-test-tube/</guid>
      <description>October brought many exciting things for me, including not only a new job, but also a new album that I’m very excited about. The Test Tubenetlabel is featuring this new release, called Gamma.
Six tracks, mostly beat-driven, of downtempo styled expressionism ripe with electro-acoustic improvisation; acousmatica for the brainwaves.
I was also honored to have Matt Mercer (of Microfilm) write up the release on Under the Lens, here’s an excerpt from the full article:</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Infinite Jest Project @ .microsound</title>
      <link>http://hpschd.xyz/2008/10/14/infinite-jest-project-microsound/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 14 Oct 2008 18:14:40 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://hpschd.xyz/2008/10/14/infinite-jest-project-microsound/</guid>
      <description>The .microsound community recently embarked on a new project to honor the life of writer David Foster Wallace, known widely for his intelligently sprawling novel Infinite Jest.
Instructions were to take one of the films attributed to the protagonist’s father and create a soundtrack. I was attracted to the surrealism in the description of Baby Pictures of Famous Dictators and almost immediately had an image of what the film would be like.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The First Place I Heard Acid Jazz Was A Steven Jesse Bernstein Record</title>
      <link>http://hpschd.xyz/2008/10/12/the-first-place-i-heard-acid-jazz-was-a-stephen-jesse-bernstein-record/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 12 Oct 2008 22:12:31 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://hpschd.xyz/2008/10/12/the-first-place-i-heard-acid-jazz-was-a-stephen-jesse-bernstein-record/</guid>
      <description>It’s true.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Updated Audio Software</title>
      <link>http://hpschd.xyz/2008/10/10/updated-audio-software/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 10 Oct 2008 18:21:10 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://hpschd.xyz/2008/10/10/updated-audio-software/</guid>
      <description>I’ve done some updates to the Audio Softwarepage, including three new categories: “Looping and Performance”, “Free Players and Visualizers” and “Programming Languages”.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Craque: “Tekuchesti” out now on Constanta</title>
      <link>http://hpschd.xyz/2008/10/03/craque-tekuchesti-out-now-on-the-constanta-netlabel/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 03 Oct 2008 17:55:59 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://hpschd.xyz/2008/10/03/craque-tekuchesti-out-now-on-the-constanta-netlabel/</guid>
      <description>I’m very happy to announce the release of a project I did this summer called Tekuchesti (a transliteration of текучести, which is a Russian word meaning “fluidity”), a piece in shuffle time for listeners and improvisers.
Download the entire work, and remember to listen on shuffle. Weird request you say? Read the liner notes below for more detail…
Please also visit the release page at Constantaand check out the other artists on this new boutique netlabel, which features some unique approaches to the microsound/glitch/experimental/drone genres; beauty through subtlety and simplicity.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Craque: “Trolling for Olives” now free download</title>
      <link>http://hpschd.xyz/2008/10/02/craque-trolling-for-olives-now-free-download/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 03 Oct 2008 01:54:44 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://hpschd.xyz/2008/10/02/craque-trolling-for-olives-now-free-download/</guid>
      <description>In 2001 the debut 12″ for Craque titled Trolling for Olives EP was released on Metatron Press, and now it’s available for free on last.fm.
All five tracks are both streamable and downloadable, I figured I’d do them all since the original is still available for purchase on vinyland it’s got some dope tracks!
And I don’t know how many of my fans actually read this, but here’s the first hint that you can expect several new releases coming up in the coming months.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>SoundHack Delay Trio Released</title>
      <link>http://hpschd.xyz/2008/09/03/soundhack-delay-trio-released/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 03 Sep 2008 22:17:24 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://hpschd.xyz/2008/09/03/soundhack-delay-trio-released/</guid>
      <description>Tom Erbeis one of the members of the electronic music community whose work I highly respect. Not only is most of his software free, not only are they usable by any skill level, not only are they the most educational electronic music tools i’ve ever used… I could go on. But the end result is that they sound simple and great.
At long last Tom has released the SoundHack Delay Trio, the description of the algorithms is fantastic, from the announcement:</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>haven’t i always written techno?</title>
      <link>http://hpschd.xyz/2008/09/02/havent-i-always-written-techno/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 02 Sep 2008 22:11:42 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://hpschd.xyz/2008/09/02/havent-i-always-written-techno/</guid>
      <description>As the summer begins its winddown, I’ve found that I’ve been writing some interesting beat-ful music at the same time I’ve been doing completely abstract sound works. It’s fun! Each opens the doors in the other, it’s pretty interesting the way the cross-over happens, and how: even moreso these days, things are sculptural and dimensional.
For long periods of time, I feel vaguely disinterested by dance music. It’s cyclical, and it makes me wonder what my music sounds like.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Experimental Music Links</title>
      <link>http://hpschd.xyz/2008/08/25/experimental-music-links/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 25 Aug 2008 23:07:01 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://hpschd.xyz/2008/08/25/experimental-music-links/</guid>
      <description>I’m usually happening upon all kinds of things while I’m across the Internets for work or play, and I’ll document the more interesting and pertinent ones here on sounding.com.
I keep my own list of interesting Audio Hardware, as well as links to useful Audio Software, a lot of which centers around open source or DIY.
Check out Audio Culture for general experimental audio society.
Get Some is my list of “obtaining” art and sound across the Internet, both pay-sites and places you can get free stuff.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Nodal: Generative MIDI software</title>
      <link>http://hpschd.xyz/2008/08/14/nodal-generative-midi-software/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 14 Aug 2008 17:20:37 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://hpschd.xyz/2008/08/14/nodal-generative-midi-software/</guid>
      <description>There’s a new generative music package out now called Nodal, which uses an object oriented interface that gives composers control over every aspect of MIDI in a string-it-together sort of Max/PD style.
It will work with any MIDI capable synth, software or hardware, which means it works with most anything like Live, GarageBand or Logic as well as your outboard synths. My outboard synths with MIDI are long gone, and I do next to no work with software synths, but it does look interesting.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Noise.io: The iPhone Synth</title>
      <link>http://hpschd.xyz/2008/08/09/noiseio-the-iphone-synth/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 09 Aug 2008 17:44:36 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://hpschd.xyz/2008/08/09/noiseio-the-iphone-synth/</guid>
      <description>The noiseforiphonelooks promising as the worlds first official iphone synth, with FM synthesis and gestural parameter adjustment.
The folks over at Noise Addicts have a nice blog entryincluding video clips and some detailed description of the four-channel FM synthesis model called “Enhanced Subspace Frequency Modulation” (ESFM).
I like that they are purposefully limiting the synth to a monophonic tool instead of a polyphonic mess; it looks like a well thought-out and highly intuitive interface, and for $7 you can’t beat it.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Bell Rung for Hiroshima</title>
      <link>http://hpschd.xyz/2008/08/06/bell-rung-for-hiroshima/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 06 Aug 2008 17:26:28 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://hpschd.xyz/2008/08/06/bell-rung-for-hiroshima/</guid>
      <description>Yesterday at 4:15PM (Pacific) I took a break from the chaos of networks and enjoyed a ceremonial oneness to honor the victims of Hiroshima in a gesture of world-wide harmony.
hiro1615080508shima starts about a minute before I rang in concert with many others across the globe for the Hiroshimia Peace Memorial Ceremony.
The recording was done in our garden walkway among our tropicals and succulents, you can hear the neighbor’s roof-top AC droning in the background, accompanied by our other neighbor’s dog.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Getting into Circuit-Bending?</title>
      <link>http://hpschd.xyz/2008/08/02/getting-into-circuit-bending/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 02 Aug 2008 18:00:56 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://hpschd.xyz/2008/08/02/getting-into-circuit-bending/</guid>
      <description>Sound Art at Anti-Theory.comprofesses to be where “the art of circuit-bending was launched on the internet,” and it’s actually a nice resource for getting into avant-garde uses of musical toys.
In [how it works]a step-by-step example shows the simple circuit-bending process, and other topics go into things like tools and equipment and advanced things about electronics.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The quake song</title>
      <link>http://hpschd.xyz/2008/07/29/the-quake-song/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 30 Jul 2008 03:09:13 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://hpschd.xyz/2008/07/29/the-quake-song/</guid>
      <description>Having moved to the LA area little over five years ago, it wasn’t until today that I experienced a significantly violent earthquake in our hometown of Fullerton – just across the freeway from the epicenter of the 5.4 quake in Chino Hills today.
I was talking on the phone in my studio for work, when suddenly it all started moving.
What’s interesting to me now is that though I remember the specific feeling of the earthquake, the adrenaline rush of anticipating when it will end, the cycles of disbelief and acceptance and small notions of what the edge of panic feels like… of all this, I remember the sounds the most.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Erotus Records Kickoff Set</title>
      <link>http://hpschd.xyz/2008/07/29/erotus-records-kickoff-set/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 29 Jul 2008 23:34:56 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://hpschd.xyz/2008/07/29/erotus-records-kickoff-set/</guid>
      <description>Here’s a live set from the guys at Erotus(Blamstrain’s new label) celebrating its launch, featured in the Viides Uuden Musiikin Festivaali, or “Fifth Festival for New Music”, held in Kupittaanpuisto, Turku, Finland.
Download itto hear area, asketix, blamstrain, ercola, and mk10 (not necessarily in that order) throw down a continuous two and a half hour set of glitch-filled, sometimes psychedelic, always atmospheric minimal techno from 25 July in Finland.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Twisted Records now has downloads</title>
      <link>http://hpschd.xyz/2008/07/26/twisted-records-now-has-downloads/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 26 Jul 2008 20:04:12 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://hpschd.xyz/2008/07/26/twisted-records-now-has-downloads/</guid>
      <description>One of my favorite sources for anything psychedelic, Twisted Records has started an online store with digital downloads.
Traditionally this has been a “DJ’s label” selling mostly vinyl and CDs of primarily music meant to be spun at a party, but it’s interesting to see them offering things digitally.
It matches up a bit with the direction of some of the music Posford and friends make now, a lot less “fringey” I’d call it – more use of pop elements some might say – not any less worldly but a lot more accessible for the common ear.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Pull of the Unexplored</title>
      <link>http://hpschd.xyz/2008/07/19/the-pull-of-the-unexplored/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 19 Jul 2008 20:08:08 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://hpschd.xyz/2008/07/19/the-pull-of-the-unexplored/</guid>
      <description>Once aspect of creativity I haven’t quite discovered how to manage is the navigation of intuition.
It strikes me that some are better than others at accessing this elusive part of the imagination. As a visceral experience it’s unmistakable, but the pathways to obtaining that level of immersion are not so clear.
Inspiration strikes at the most incredulous opportunity; sometimes it’s like a pull, like gravitation towards a goal not seen, being drawn into a feeling that is indescribable beyond the need to create.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Soaking Tide</title>
      <link>http://hpschd.xyz/2008/07/14/soaking-tide/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 14 Jul 2008 07:55:57 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://hpschd.xyz/2008/07/14/soaking-tide/</guid>
      <description>One of my favorite pastimes recently is surfing through social sites like last.fm, following neighbor and friend links to different people’s pages and friends and neighbors and so on and so on… it’s a fascinating and sometimes recursive journey through the tastes of like minded individuals.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Splay</title>
      <link>http://hpschd.xyz/2008/07/09/splay/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 10 Jul 2008 02:19:18 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://hpschd.xyz/2008/07/09/splay/</guid>
      <description>I am infused from all directions it seems, there is so much to do.
At times there seem to be so many directions that I cannot find a clear path; when I dream to be great at something, but feel I have no focus on anything.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>New Release: Material</title>
      <link>http://hpschd.xyz/2008/07/09/new-release-material/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 09 Jul 2008 22:12:20 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://hpschd.xyz/2008/07/09/new-release-material/</guid>
      <description>Since this release came out while my blog was unavailable, thought I would shout it out that a new Craque album called Materialis available on Kahvi Collective! From the website:
 “Guest artist craque arrives on Kahvi Collective with a unique blend of textures and IDM elements. Five track ‘Material’ verges on the style of ‘MigloJE’. Torus Europa sets the scene with its lush, drawn out passages of sound and textures and leads into the interesting ‘strawberry jam’, an atonal melody drawing on a paced bass line which makes a nice combination and the extraordinary ‘organum’ (my personal favourite of this release) with ‘that’ sample hook that fits so well with the rest of the track.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>DIY photo-sensitive synth</title>
      <link>http://hpschd.xyz/2008/07/08/diy-photo-sensitive-synth/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 08 Jul 2008 21:33:02 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://hpschd.xyz/2008/07/08/diy-photo-sensitive-synth/</guid>
      <description>I’m excited to be waiting on the arrival of my new Bleep Labs ThingamaKIT.
Not unlike the simple improvising synth I’ve been working on with VCOs and 2-pole filters, this is a DIY version of their photo-sensitive thingamagoop, described on their website as simply:
“The Thingamagoops have oscillators just like any synth. On analog synths the oscillator that creates the actual tone you hear is called a VCO or voltage controlled oscillator.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Welcome to the New Sound</title>
      <link>http://hpschd.xyz/2008/07/06/welcome-to-the-new-sound/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 06 Jul 2008 23:31:01 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://hpschd.xyz/2008/07/06/welcome-to-the-new-sound/</guid>
      <description>You may have noticed a slight change in interface on the blog here, it’s because I switched from the TWiki BlogPlugin to WordPress.
The basic reason is that although BlogPlugin is a great tool on TWiki, it’s not as fully featured as I’d like, and there is the overhead of several dependencies within TWiki. The latter reason is difficult to deal with between system crashes and other kinds of data loss, and instead of banging my head against infinite loops in perl ImageMagick, I opted to install WP.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Craque DJ set: Stop Time CD release party</title>
      <link>http://hpschd.xyz/2008/05/23/craque-dj-set-stop-time-cd-release-party/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 23 May 2008 17:20:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://hpschd.xyz/2008/05/23/craque-dj-set-stop-time-cd-release-party/</guid>
      <description>Wednesday night I played after John Harrington’s Stop Time for their CD release party, you can hear the 2-hour set new on CraqueCastor downloadthe full thing directly.
I also have several picturesfrom the gig for all to see… John moves ALL THE TIME so my little digital camera could never get a clean shot of him!
As many of you may know, I improvise all my DJ sets. So I almost never have a full set list, because I’m just going with the flow.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>New Releases on Metatron: Joe Zitt, GWME</title>
      <link>http://hpschd.xyz/2008/05/16/new-releases-on-metatron-joe-zitt-gwme/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 16 May 2008 17:57:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://hpschd.xyz/2008/05/16/new-releases-on-metatron-joe-zitt-gwme/</guid>
      <description>Metatron Press has re-released a few more recordings on archive.org:
  Collaborationsfeatures Joseph Zitt’s vocals and improvisations with such musicians as F. Vattel Cherry, members of Gray Code, and an electronica treatment by Craque.
  Gusty Winds May Existconsists of Comma member Tom Bickley on recorders and electronics with Nancy Beckman on shakuhachi. This is the first in a series of three releases by each member of Comma with hand-made packaging and album design by Joe Zitt.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>T Spigot is rearing its burroughsian head once again</title>
      <link>http://hpschd.xyz/2008/05/14/t-spigot-is-rearing-its-burroughsian-head-once-again/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 14 May 2008 18:31:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://hpschd.xyz/2008/05/14/t-spigot-is-rearing-its-burroughsian-head-once-again/</guid>
      <description>My favorite live downtempo band – T Spigot – is back in action this year, and to start it off they’re offering the limited edition first pressing of Experiments in the Hypnotic Production of Crime, available through paypalfor a measly $5, so go get it!
The bonus is that this version of the album includes the remix of dubnbud which they did for the 12″ release of Trolling for Olives.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Metatron Press releases Gray Code on archive.org</title>
      <link>http://hpschd.xyz/2008/04/17/metatron-press-releases-gray-code-on-archiveorg/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 17 Apr 2008 20:02:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://hpschd.xyz/2008/04/17/metatron-press-releases-gray-code-on-archiveorg/</guid>
      <description>Metatron Press(the website is slightly outdated, but not necessarily incorrect) has started a netlabel archive, posting releases formerly available only on CDR, as well as more new stuff to come.
A quintet I played in for some time called Gray Code now has a live recording up, from the 2000 Philadelphia Fringe Festival.
The name of the group is taken from the structure we often used to improvise: “In performances using the Gray Code structure for five players, we proceed through all the possible combinations of members of the group, including the silence that starts and ends the performance, five solos, ten duets, ten trios, five quartets, and the single quintet involving all the players.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Tangent and an Improv Rig</title>
      <link>http://hpschd.xyz/2008/02/01/tangent-and-an-improv-rig/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 02 Feb 2008 02:56:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://hpschd.xyz/2008/02/01/tangent-and-an-improv-rig/</guid>
      <description>The synth used for my Feb 8 show at Dangerous Curve, incorporated in my live electro-acoustic rig. There’s a last.fm video of the showthat actually has pretty decent sound!
What you see below is my homebuilt synth (three square wave oscillators fed through dual 2-pole lowpass filters, each metal box has an engage switch, tone control, and cutoff frequency) fed through (or not) a Boss AW-3 dynamic wah filter, an acoustic guitar contact microphone fed through (or not) an AudiobulbFZ-Bulb, a pocket shortwave radio, several found objects (near and in the tin can), and behind that a Line6 DL4, Electrix Repeater, Alesis Quadraverb and Behringer Xenyx 1622 mixer.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>New Release: Density Operator</title>
      <link>http://hpschd.xyz/2008/01/20/new-release-density-operator/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 21 Jan 2008 06:09:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://hpschd.xyz/2008/01/20/new-release-density-operator/</guid>
      <description>Behold the appalling beautiful world of Density Operator now available on Stadtgruen.
“The title is program: everything in this world seems to be under pressure in order to extract the highest concentration of agility. Computer sounds are algorithms, just another form of mathematical strings. Thus the densification of sound works by finding the shortest possible expression.”
Music on this album picked its own paths and themes as it emerged from ideas I’ve had about quantum mechanics and atomic theory, and how the same conceptual mindspace is occupied by the intense spontaneity of improvisation.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>RIP: Loungeometry at the Kettle and the Keg</title>
      <link>http://hpschd.xyz/2008/01/16/rip-loungeometry-at-the-kettle-and-the-keg/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 16 Jan 2008 22:32:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://hpschd.xyz/2008/01/16/rip-loungeometry-at-the-kettle-and-the-keg/</guid>
      <description>In response to the many sad emails and messages about Loungeometry, the evident is true: Kettle and the Keg has decided on their own to forgo lounge music to try and bring in more customer base. Loungeometry has been discontinued.
At a certain level, the finger can be pointed at the City of Fullerton. Incentives for business to open downtown, efforts to revitalize and bring consumers into the city, extensive renovation projects and residential development… all these things have brought an enormous influx of people, and merchants are struggling to compete for their wallets in the only way they know how: bait them with popular culture.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>New on CraqueCast: Amalgamation</title>
      <link>http://hpschd.xyz/2008/01/09/new-on-craquecast-amalgamation/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 09 Jan 2008 21:17:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://hpschd.xyz/2008/01/09/new-on-craquecast-amalgamation/</guid>
      <description>Starting off the new year with an archival live show: Amalgamation: Live at Smartbar, Chicago, 2002 is a set I did at SmartBarin March of 2002.
This is a set where I combined many influences, methods and directions together through a wide assortment of sampled objects, guitar playing, voices, and softsynths. It’s glitchy, ambient, dark, funky, beaty and bouncy all at the same time! A really nice listen with highly contrasting sections of sound and rhythm.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>December So Far</title>
      <link>http://hpschd.xyz/2007/12/19/december-so-far/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 19 Dec 2007 20:26:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://hpschd.xyz/2007/12/19/december-so-far/</guid>
      <description>Well I know you could just go through my Last.fm listening or whatever, but it doesn’t represent everything. So this isn’t a best-of by any stretch, just a viewfinder into what I’ve been listening to the past 3 weeks. They’re loosely grouped by category… I’ll let the reader decide how to categorize them. Tags: listening</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The amazing things people say to a DJ</title>
      <link>http://hpschd.xyz/2007/12/14/the-amazing-things-people-say-to-a-dj/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 14 Dec 2007 18:19:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://hpschd.xyz/2007/12/14/the-amazing-things-people-say-to-a-dj/</guid>
      <description>I don’t know whether to call this sad or a sign of the times (surely it’s both), but if nothing else it certainly makes me feel on the fringe (of what, I am not sure) moreso than ever. Now I’ve noticed in particular that girls who come up asking if I take requests don’t listen to my answer and ask if I have this or that, or act surprised that I don’t have anything you can hear on the radio.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Circuitbend ahoy!</title>
      <link>http://hpschd.xyz/2007/12/08/circuitbend-ahoy/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 09 Dec 2007 03:26:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://hpschd.xyz/2007/12/08/circuitbend-ahoy/</guid>
      <description>I’ve now dived pretty headlong into the world of circuit bending and synthesis, and it’s hooked me. There’s a unique similarity between creating digital and analog sounds with circuits and finding sounds with microphones on objects, so I’m motivated on the ideas behind what one friend so rightly calls my “tinkering”. What’s on the bench now is a small, multi-oscillator synth, probably with a movable filter. This will sit some how on my ever-evolving soundboard and contribute to the medium.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>CraqueCast: Craque &#43; Viv &#43; Carol</title>
      <link>http://hpschd.xyz/2007/11/05/craquecast-craque-viv-carol/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 05 Nov 2007 23:42:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://hpschd.xyz/2007/11/05/craquecast-craque-viv-carol/</guid>
      <description>The CraqueCast for October/November 2007 features Matt Cooke-Davis (voice, sampled objects and electronics), Carol Genetti (voice) and Viv Corringham (voice) in a three-part free improvisation at The Nervous Center Festival of Electronic Music, Chicago 2002. Viv is a vocal experimenter from the UK who I met through Pauline Oliveros and the Deep Listening group, and has done some interesting work with ‘walkabout’ listening and binaural recording. Carol is a Chicago-area vocalist who has worked with many other free improvisors and electronic musicians, we met through the improv scene there and were excited to do some collaboration for the Nervous Center.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Modular Synth meets Wii Controller</title>
      <link>http://hpschd.xyz/2007/09/20/modular-synth-meets-wii-controller/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 20 Sep 2007 22:51:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://hpschd.xyz/2007/09/20/modular-synth-meets-wii-controller/</guid>
      <description>Here is a very well produced video showing someone who has used bluetooth and scripting to control a Doepfermodular synthesizer with a Wii controller. DOEP! Tags: video, analog, controllers</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>So you wanna control buttons?</title>
      <link>http://hpschd.xyz/2007/09/17/so-you-wanna-control-buttons/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 18 Sep 2007 02:01:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://hpschd.xyz/2007/09/17/so-you-wanna-control-buttons/</guid>
      <description>Since I first started manipulating live samples, I’ve always wanted some kind of trigger surface that’s nothing but a bunch of dumb buttons that trigger samples via internal bank or MIDI. For a long time I’ve been using loopers and other devices to gather and playback samples. But nowadays I’m looking at changing around my live setup, and think I’d really like to add a ‘sample bank’ to the config so I can work with pre-made samples as well as live-sampled sounds.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Listening on</title>
      <link>http://hpschd.xyz/2007/08/13/listening-on/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 14 Aug 2007 02:07:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://hpschd.xyz/2007/08/13/listening-on/</guid>
      <description>some recent releases on digital i’m enjoying. some brand new, some not so new, but they keep me coming back:   Kim Cascone has a special way of writing music like the sound of crumpling paper, here stratified by field recordings on The Astrum Argentum. I’m especially drawn to the sounds in this recording, especially how conscious-close they are to escaping all original form; the experienced listener expertly removes themselves from reality with kim’s music.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Networking ideas at Ramp</title>
      <link>http://hpschd.xyz/2007/06/28/networking-ideas-at-ramp/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 28 Jun 2007 21:07:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://hpschd.xyz/2007/06/28/networking-ideas-at-ramp/</guid>
      <description>Liz Revision, aka Quantazellehas a new DJ residency at Ramp Chicago, a monthly night at Sonothequefeaturing “ambient, IDM, electro and quirky, glitchy techno.” Yes, good music remains alive in Chi-town!!! Congrats first off to Lizfor the residency! If you know her music but don’t know her jewelry design, check out the goods at Fractalspin. I like them because she does similar things with jewelry that I’ve applied so some of my sculpture.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Brian Eno’s 77 million and the Mac</title>
      <link>http://hpschd.xyz/2007/06/21/brian-enos-77-million-and-the-mac/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 21 Jun 2007 18:15:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://hpschd.xyz/2007/06/21/brian-enos-77-million-and-the-mac/</guid>
      <description>If you’re in San Fran, do not miss the North American premiere of Brian Eno’s 77 Million Paintingsexhibit at the Yerba Buena Center for the Artsthe weekend of June 29th. This looks like a fantastic thing, what’s even cooler is that it’s all done with Macs!You can also buy the work on DVD, but obviously it was meant for a grand space. Details of the event are on the Long Now Foundation website.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Ambiguity</title>
      <link>http://hpschd.xyz/p1222/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://hpschd.xyz/p1222/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>I ate DevOps</title>
      <link>http://hpschd.xyz/p1110/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://hpschd.xyz/p1110/</guid>
      <description>“Music collector” is probably how I would classify myself. Streaming music is good in a pinch (I prefer SomaFMwhen it comes to curated radio listening [disclaimer: my musicis often in rotation on CliqHop]), but my primary source of listening is my modest personal collection: 300GB+ of digital files, a quarter of which are CD rips of only about a sixth of my dust-gathering CD folders, and thousands of vinyl records. I seek out things, I follow threads of interest, I pay attention to collaborators and studio players and remixers to find other things that might interest me.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Ok, DevOps</title>
      <link>http://hpschd.xyz/p1098/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://hpschd.xyz/p1098/</guid>
      <description>I have a story to tell about DevOps.
I’m one of those people who pioneered the Internet. I don’t say that lightly or in jest. It is I, among many others, that began building the infrastructure and caring for myriad companies of the early “commercial” Internet, taking commerce, collaboration, design, and information sharing forward.
I’ll give you an idea. When I worked for GlobalCenter in the 1990s, I once walked by a cage our team had built that was something like 20ft square and contained a single rack in the middle, surrounded by box-fans.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>So What?</title>
      <link>http://hpschd.xyz/p906/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://hpschd.xyz/p906/</guid>
      <description>One of my favorite Miles Davis heads is this song where the bass leads the melody and everything else falls into place. I always liked this tune because the bass was the first voice, and you know the piece because of it. When I listen to – or in rare occasions play – this magnificent thing, I’m reminded of the simplicity of improvisation. How chord changes are chord changes, but a solo can be made of a single note.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Stagehand Syndrome</title>
      <link>http://hpschd.xyz/p1115/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://hpschd.xyz/p1115/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Complification of Simplicity</title>
      <link>http://hpschd.xyz/p985/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://hpschd.xyz/p985/</guid>
      <description>Creating things is a fundamental human activity. In music, it includes many things: composition, instrumentation, preparation, production, performance, presentation, recording, distribution, consumption, listening… just to name a few. In fact, the expression of a piece of music can very quickly become a complex weave of tree-like dependencies, where many different disciplines – and humans – combine to create a unified work.
Over time, technologies advanced quickly, and improvements to the various sub-fields within making a musical work crossed boundaries.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>