<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Craque on Sounding</title>
    <link>https://sounding.com/tags/craque/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Craque on Sounding</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 20 Sep 2010 00:57:25 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://sounding.com/tags/craque/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>just some synth</title>
      <link>https://sounding.com/2010/09/19/just-some-synth/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 20 Sep 2010 00:57:25 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://sounding.com/2010/09/19/just-some-synth/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>New Instruments</title>
      <link>https://sounding.com/2010/08/06/new-instruments/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 07 Aug 2010 06:11:05 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://sounding.com/2010/08/06/new-instruments/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Appearing in variety…</title>
      <link>https://sounding.com/2009/07/02/appearing-in-variety/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 03 Jul 2009 00:33:17 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://sounding.com/2009/07/02/appearing-in-variety/</guid>
      <description>Audiobulb has released a free sampler of music from eight artists on the label, including a track off Supple (see post below), subtly arranged and expertly mixed by label owner David Newman. Others included are: Jimmy Behan, Biosphere, Ultre, NQ, Mark Harris, Hans van Eck and He Can Jog. I’m honored to be among the talent in that lineup, and the music is just awesome.
Also recently, Xynthetic produced their Second Statement, a stunning cross-section of the artist roster that displays the wide variety to be had on the netlabel.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>“Supple” out now on Audiobulb</title>
      <link>https://sounding.com/2009/04/07/supple-out-now-on-audiobulb/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 08 Apr 2009 02:45:35 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://sounding.com/2009/04/07/supple-out-now-on-audiobulb/</guid>
      <description>Presenting: an electro-acoustic album of experimental sound sources and improvisations punctuated by iterative percussion, i.e. glitchy ambient slightly funky dance music. 😉
Supple is the way I’ve seen things come together over several years after moving to California, and owes some to dance forms that made this area of the country so important to electronic music development and culture. They are presented in a sort of story-form (I’ll blame my operatic tendencies for that), where endings and beginnings aren’t so easily discerned, and overall structure blends them in a sort of high-contrast, watercolor way… which I think is matched in visual form by gl0tch (check out the release page to see different versions of the cover art morphing), giving it all this primordial evolutionary cybernetic aspect that I love, as if everything is a petri dish of mechanically chaotic musical questions.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Downtempo from the Studio</title>
      <link>https://sounding.com/2009/03/17/downtempo-from-the-studio/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 17 Mar 2009 21:45:15 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://sounding.com/2009/03/17/downtempo-from-the-studio/</guid>
      <description>I’ve set up a set in Soundcloud called “Downtempo Excursions” to post some sonic paintings created with free improvisation and minimal beats.
 Let me know what you think! These are sort of what I’d call “composting” of materials, kaleidoscopically tapestristic, experimentally structured.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Coming soon… Craque on Audiobulb</title>
      <link>https://sounding.com/2008/12/17/coming-soon-craque-on-audiobulb/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 18 Dec 2008 02:17:53 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://sounding.com/2008/12/17/coming-soon-craque-on-audiobulb/</guid>
      <description>So my new full-length album, Supple, will be released by Audiobulb in March of 2009. Ain’t that awesome! It’s a real honor to be joining in the ranks of Autistici, HeCanJog, Ultre, Calika, and so many others.
Months have gone by (actually, no, YEARS) where I have absorbed things, seen new parts of the world, learned new techniques, sought out what’s further; and this album evolved alongside me. The entire work has grown from single tracks and loose groupings to continuity and connection through thematic reverberation, it’s been fun and full of discovery.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Craque: “Tekuchesti” out now on Constanta</title>
      <link>https://sounding.com/2008/10/03/craque-tekuchesti-out-now-on-the-constanta-netlabel/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 03 Oct 2008 17:55:59 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://sounding.com/2008/10/03/craque-tekuchesti-out-now-on-the-constanta-netlabel/</guid>
      <description>I’m very happy to announce the release of a project I did this summer called Tekuchesti (a transliteration of текучести, which is a Russian word meaning “fluidity”), a piece in shuffle time for listeners and improvisers.
Download the entire work, and remember to listen on shuffle. Weird request you say? Read the liner notes below for more detail…
Please also visit the release page at Constanta and check out the other artists on this new boutique netlabel, which features some unique approaches to the microsound/glitch/experimental/drone genres; beauty through subtlety and simplicity.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Craque: “Trolling for Olives” now free download</title>
      <link>https://sounding.com/2008/10/02/craque-trolling-for-olives-now-free-download/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 03 Oct 2008 01:54:44 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://sounding.com/2008/10/02/craque-trolling-for-olives-now-free-download/</guid>
      <description>In 2001 the debut 12″ for Craque titled Trolling for Olives EP was released on Metatron Press, and now it’s available for free on last.fm.
All five tracks are both streamable and downloadable, I figured I’d do them all since the original is still available for purchase on vinyl and it’s got some dope tracks!
And I don’t know how many of my fans actually read this, but here’s the first hint that you can expect several new releases coming up in the coming months.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>