<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>chaosengineering on Sounding</title>
    <link>https://sounding.com/tags/chaosengineering/</link>
    <description>Recent content in chaosengineering on Sounding</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 11 Sep 2019 20:39:41 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://sounding.com/tags/chaosengineering/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Musical City Techno</title>
      <link>https://sounding.com/2019/09/11/musical-city-techno/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 11 Sep 2019 20:39:41 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://sounding.com/2019/09/11/musical-city-techno/</guid>
      <description>Fanny&amp;#8217;s Music, East Nashville
  Cicada, cricket, grasshopper, frog. However that particular indeterminate carpet of sound occurs, it is a permanent feature of the American South. I grew up in this soup, so hearing this familiar symphony again after nearly two decades of being away felt surreal and magical.
It is the sound that framed my stay in Nashville, Music City, for three mini-conferences all held at once at the Nossi College of Art: Music City Agile, Music City Code, and Music City Data.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Weirdness of Experiment</title>
      <link>https://sounding.com/2019/02/22/weirdness-of-experiment/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 23 Feb 2019 06:47:26 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://sounding.com/2019/02/22/weirdness-of-experiment/</guid>
      <description>My job in ops has always been to keep things running. I never considered myself “working in software”, but have recently begun embracing the fact that I do. What I accomplish as an operations and infrastructure engineer is part of the system, it isn’t dislocated from its composition.
Relatedly, I have been considering the nature of the experiment in Chaos Engineering. How continuous verification is becoming a crucial part of the complex systems we build because there really is no end.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Musical Intuition meet Technology and Chaos</title>
      <link>https://sounding.com/2018/12/26/musical-intuition-meet-technology-and-chaos/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 27 Dec 2018 02:57:40 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://sounding.com/2018/12/26/musical-intuition-meet-technology-and-chaos/</guid>
      <description>Today I read through the InfoQ eMag on Chaos Engineering, and was struck by John Allspaw’s (@allspaw) contribution because it reminded me of something I jotted down on a sticky at my desk a few days ago:
 Intuition is valid because it is learned like jazz changes.  I’m pretty stubborn and refuse to accept that music is merely a hobby of mine. When people ask me if electronic music or singing is my “hobby”, I am wincing inside.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>