<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>microsound on Sounding</title>
    <link>https://sounding.com/tags/microsound/</link>
    <description>Recent content in microsound on Sounding</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Fri, 03 Jul 2009 00:33:17 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://sounding.com/tags/microsound/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Appearing in variety…</title>
      <link>https://sounding.com/2009/07/02/appearing-in-variety/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 03 Jul 2009 00:33:17 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://sounding.com/2009/07/02/appearing-in-variety/</guid>
      <description>Audiobulb has released a free sampler of music from eight artists on the label, including a track off Supple (see post below), subtly arranged and expertly mixed by label owner David Newman. Others included are: Jimmy Behan, Biosphere, Ultre, NQ, Mark Harris, Hans van Eck and He Can Jog. I’m honored to be among the talent in that lineup, and the music is just awesome.
Also recently, Xynthetic produced their Second Statement, a stunning cross-section of the artist roster that displays the wide variety to be had on the netlabel.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>New improvisations on SoundCloud</title>
      <link>https://sounding.com/2009/02/21/new-improvisations-on-soundcloud/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 21 Feb 2009 19:10:57 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://sounding.com/2009/02/21/new-improvisations-on-soundcloud/</guid>
      <description>Freely improvised one-takes. Instrumentation includes homebuilt instruments, sampled objects and looping hardware.
 This music sharing site is a great tool for posting various non-published tracks, as well as released stuff, and has a nice embeddable player and comment system. Really nice for being able to just slap some stuff up, I have one friend who has recently been doing the same with sessions on his new Serge Modular Creature, and another who posted “in progress” snapshots of a track he is working on.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Infinite Jest Project @ .microsound</title>
      <link>https://sounding.com/2008/10/14/infinite-jest-project-microsound/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 14 Oct 2008 18:14:40 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://sounding.com/2008/10/14/infinite-jest-project-microsound/</guid>
      <description>The .microsound community recently embarked on a new project to honor the life of writer David Foster Wallace, known widely for his intelligently sprawling novel Infinite Jest.
Instructions were to take one of the films attributed to the protagonist’s father and create a soundtrack. I was attracted to the surrealism in the description of Baby Pictures of Famous Dictators and almost immediately had an image of what the film would be like.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>