<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>performance on Sounding</title>
    <link>https://sounding.com/categories/performance/</link>
    <description>Recent content in performance on Sounding</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Fri, 16 Aug 2019 03:00:13 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://sounding.com/categories/performance/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Meta Workshop Jam</title>
      <link>https://sounding.com/2019/08/15/meta-workshop-jam/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 16 Aug 2019 03:00:13 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://sounding.com/2019/08/15/meta-workshop-jam/</guid>
      <description>Me at the Palace of Fine Arts, workshop eve  Walking late one afternoon after a day deep in Cognitive Systems and Resilience Engineering workshops, chatting with one of the eminent researchers in the field, the conversation circled around common ground in joint activity and sociotechnical systems sharing qualities with music ensembles. I remember agreeing how some uncategorizable thing exists on both sides as an outcome, where a result far greater than merely the sum of its parts occurs.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>MusiCirTechUs</title>
      <link>https://sounding.com/2019/03/21/musicirtechus/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 22 Mar 2019 02:00:23 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://sounding.com/2019/03/21/musicirtechus/</guid>
      <description>Plenty of people who work in technology are musicians. Plenty of humans are musicians, and all of us are listening, even those who cannot hear. In my travels through datacenters and software, I have come across musicians like myself who have not only done double-duty with their computer science and creative lives but also relate and interweave them. If they’re like me, they cannot break them apart. There are hundreds, if not thousands, of us.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Living 4’33”</title>
      <link>https://sounding.com/2019/01/19/living-433/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 19 Jan 2019 08:10:42 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://sounding.com/2019/01/19/living-433/</guid>
      <description>I haven’t experienced Mute’s STUMM433 release yet, it’s not due out until May. The proceeds from its sale go to charities, so that’s a big huge plus for it already. Pulling big names like Depeche Mode and Moby will hopefully make for good sales.
This is also not the first time 4’33” has been “recorded” for the purpose of a record release and not as part of a live performance. Frank Zappa has done it, Pauline Oliveros and the Deep Listening Band plus others, and some even got sued for it.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Musical Intuition meet Technology and Chaos</title>
      <link>https://sounding.com/2018/12/26/musical-intuition-meet-technology-and-chaos/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 27 Dec 2018 02:57:40 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://sounding.com/2018/12/26/musical-intuition-meet-technology-and-chaos/</guid>
      <description>Today I read through the InfoQ eMag on Chaos Engineering, and was struck by John Allspaw’s (@allspaw) contribution because it reminded me of something I jotted down on a sticky at my desk a few days ago:
 Intuition is valid because it is learned like jazz changes.  I’m pretty stubborn and refuse to accept that music is merely a hobby of mine. When people ask me if electronic music or singing is my “hobby”, I am wincing inside.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>LA Phil graces Cage’s Europeras 1 &amp; 2</title>
      <link>https://sounding.com/2018/11/14/la-phil-graces-cages-europeras-1-2/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 15 Nov 2018 06:46:48 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://sounding.com/2018/11/14/la-phil-graces-cages-europeras-1-2/</guid>
      <description>John Cage liked to borrow. Whether in musical style or approach to theatre, the materials themselves are often not his. Musical scores evolved into graphic iconography or instruction governed by brackets of time and/or duration. Written pieces were amalgamations, mesostics “written through” other authors’ work, or more “cut-up” style constructions of various texts.
It applied to his philosophies, too. He is known to take bits and pieces of Eastern practice and weave their concepts into his worldview and compositional process.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Fullerton Art Walk Menagerie</title>
      <link>https://sounding.com/2012/04/08/fullerton-art-walk-menagerie/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 09 Apr 2012 01:00:57 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://sounding.com/2012/04/08/fullerton-art-walk-menagerie/</guid>
      <description>Here’s my own collection of aural glass animals for you to enjoy… a mix of groovy and beaty dreamscapes (3:38 @ 256K cbr mp3), recorded live for the Fullerton Art Walk on Friday (April 6), accompanying tattoo artist Jon Kelly (known for Olde Tyme Tattoo) as he applies his latest in biomechanical fashion.
=== e d i t ===
…by the way a vinyl mix…
 </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>120 Hours For John Cage</title>
      <link>https://sounding.com/2012/02/14/120-hours-for-john-cage/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 14 Feb 2012 22:55:58 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://sounding.com/2012/02/14/120-hours-for-john-cage/</guid>
      <description>As you may or may not know, 2012 is the Centennial of John Cage’s birth, and among its many celebrants (including myself, details to come…) is “transmission arts” collective Free103point9, who work in conjunction with WGXC 90.7-FM in upstate New York to present works specifically designed for air-borne electro-magnetic transmission – Radio, that is.
As you also may or may not know, John Cage wrote an abundance of pieces that called for either radios as instruments or as the listening medium (i.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Ubuweb posts Greenaway’s 4 American Composers</title>
      <link>https://sounding.com/2011/12/08/ubuweb-posts-greenaways-4-american-composers/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 08 Dec 2011 16:40:26 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://sounding.com/2011/12/08/ubuweb-posts-greenaways-4-american-composers/</guid>
      <description>Back in the mid 90’s before I ever got into techno music, I owned the original VHS copy of Peter Greenaway’s 1983 release 4merican Composers (natch, “Four American Composers”) and watched it constantly while in music school; I think I probably saw the Cage movie no less than 10 times.
As a honorable musicologist is want to do, I lent my copy out to a friend who had never heard of any of them, but then never got it back because of moving across the country.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>SoundWalk 2011 is coming</title>
      <link>https://sounding.com/2011/08/31/soundwalk-2011-is-coming/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 31 Aug 2011 18:01:36 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://sounding.com/2011/08/31/soundwalk-2011-is-coming/</guid>
      <description>Just in case you missed it, SoundWalk Long Beach 2011 is just around the corner! Check out the newly posted set of mp3’s from last year’s event at craque.net (or download a zip file of flac files directly).
Here’s a couple of pix from last year’s event…
[][2]Craque performing at SoundWalk 2010 in Long Beach, CA [][3]Dave doubles as stagehand and soundmaker improvisor [][4]Later in the evening, up close with participants </description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>