<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>creativity on Sounding</title>
    <link>https://sounding.com/categories/creativity/</link>
    <description>Recent content in creativity on Sounding</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sun, 17 May 2020 22:40:20 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://sounding.com/categories/creativity/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Anti-Bias of Listening Deeply</title>
      <link>https://sounding.com/2020/05/17/anti-bias-of-listening-deeply/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 17 May 2020 22:40:20 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://sounding.com/2020/05/17/anti-bias-of-listening-deeply/</guid>
      <description>Getting around cognitive biases (like “hindsight is 20/20” or a confirmation you expect) is akin to Listening Deeply. I don’t mean paying more attention gives better insight. I mean what matters is the entirety of your sonic awareness.

There is a composer / meditative approach to sound pioneered by Pauline Oliveros called Deep Listening. I have practiced it, all too briefly with her, but mostly with others taught by her.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Meander Sonor Ode</title>
      <link>https://sounding.com/2019/09/07/meander-sonor-ode/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 08 Sep 2019 05:12:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://sounding.com/2019/09/07/meander-sonor-ode/</guid>
      <description>(a listening deeply gift from the urban inside)
A speaker faced down the bench
where we sat, directly
adjacent to the Duet. Their aging laptops looping maybe scooping
the sound from their devices,
strung and hung in air plus wired,
synth sound supple and rounded
towards their combined long-tone sculpting. As the bench began to resonate,
this pool of glacial tones clustering
and extended found the grains
of smooth planked architecture,</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Meta Workshop Jam</title>
      <link>https://sounding.com/2019/08/15/meta-workshop-jam/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 16 Aug 2019 03:00:13 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://sounding.com/2019/08/15/meta-workshop-jam/</guid>
      <description>Walking late one afternoon after a day deep in Cognitive Systems and Resilience Engineering workshops, chatting with one of the eminent researchers in the field, the conversation circled around common ground in joint activity and sociotechnical systems sharing qualities with music ensembles. I remember agreeing how some uncategorizable thing exists on both sides as an outcome, where a result far greater than merely the sum of its parts occurs.
Music isn’t just the combination of the instruments, it’s the way in which humans push their operation forward through time both creating and adapting to the music and each other simultaneously.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Pickles for Adam</title>
      <link>https://sounding.com/2019/04/02/pickles-for-adam/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 03 Apr 2019 05:41:04 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://sounding.com/2019/04/02/pickles-for-adam/</guid>
      <description>(on the occasion of our meeting and bridge crossing)
Vinegar still rhythm
Sounds in parallel
Sticks shove and
Pucker.
Twiddling stone across
Steps to below regions
Glass smoothly to Airwaves.
Pentatonic organum
Slides the rails aside
Bringing touches on
Reedlings.
Air patterns float around
Silent eyes and finds
Lowly tones with
Grains.
Fermented time brings
Succulent and sprung
Rocks melting or
Clicking.
Repeat and distracted
Silver round reflective
Cover glimpse for</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>MusiCirTechUs</title>
      <link>https://sounding.com/2019/03/21/musicirtechus/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 22 Mar 2019 02:00:23 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://sounding.com/2019/03/21/musicirtechus/</guid>
      <description>Plenty of people who work in technology are musicians. Plenty of humans are musicians, and all of us are listening, even those who cannot hear. In my travels through datacenters and software, I have come across musicians like myself who have not only done double-duty with their computer science and creative lives but also relate and interweave them. If they’re like me, they cannot break them apart. There are hundreds, if not thousands, of us.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>So You Want 10 Albums?</title>
      <link>https://sounding.com/2019/01/01/so-you-want-10-albums/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 02 Jan 2019 05:01:29 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://sounding.com/2019/01/01/so-you-want-10-albums/</guid>
      <description>Ok Bob. You asked for it. With one caveat.
In no particular order, post 10 of your favorite albums, one per day, which made an impact on you. Post cover, no explanation, nominate someone each day to do the challenge.  I think these games are fascinating windows into peoples’ aesthetic, but because of FB’s sorting and selection criteria, I see maybe TWO of a particular friend’s ten-albums-once-per-day series. So, if I am taking the time to compile, I want to make sure you see them all.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Ubuweb posts Greenaway’s 4 American Composers</title>
      <link>https://sounding.com/2011/12/08/ubuweb-posts-greenaways-4-american-composers/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 08 Dec 2011 16:40:26 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://sounding.com/2011/12/08/ubuweb-posts-greenaways-4-american-composers/</guid>
      <description>Back in the mid 90’s before I ever got into techno music, I owned the original VHS copy of Peter Greenaway’s 1983 release 4merican Composers (natch, “Four American Composers”) and watched it constantly while in music school; I think I probably saw the Cage movie no less than 10 times.
As a honorable musicologist is want to do, I lent my copy out to a friend who had never heard of any of them, but then never got it back because of moving across the country.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Morton Subotnick Interviewed</title>
      <link>https://sounding.com/2011/11/29/morton-subotnick-interviewed/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 30 Nov 2011 01:08:05 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://sounding.com/2011/11/29/morton-subotnick-interviewed/</guid>
      <description>This is a great interview of an awesome figure in electronic music, done just recently (2011) in Madrid by the Red Bull Music Academy:
Listen to a free stream of Silver Apples of the Moon on last.fm.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Why am I silent?</title>
      <link>https://sounding.com/2010/11/09/why-am-i-silent/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 10 Nov 2010 05:46:53 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://sounding.com/2010/11/09/why-am-i-silent/</guid>
      <description>Incredibly, when I was a young boy I assumed everyone was supposed to know everything. It wasn’t until I was probably 30 that I realized things are meant to be learned and practiced, never known outright or assumed to be perfect.
But I spent a long time growing up thinking the opposite, that because I didn’t know something meant I couldn’t belong.
When I was thirteen, between finishing The Lord of the Rings and discovering Playboy, I locked onto a character in David Eddings’s The Belgariad; a wizardly type bloke who espoused silence and the ability to listen, leaving speech to those who knew not how to think.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>creating obsessive beauty</title>
      <link>https://sounding.com/2010/10/15/creating-obsessive-beauty/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 16 Oct 2010 03:58:59 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://sounding.com/2010/10/15/creating-obsessive-beauty/</guid>
      <description>I happen to be a voracious reader. I would probably write more if I didn’t read so much. One thing I’ve noticed is the tendency to obsess on a single writer’s work: someone or something will turn me on to a specific author, I’ll read one of his or her works, and immediately want to read everything they’ve ever done. On occasion I accomplish this, but sometimes the task is simply too great.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Importance of Computer Silence</title>
      <link>https://sounding.com/2009/12/07/the-importance-of-computer-silence/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 07 Dec 2009 19:48:25 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://sounding.com/2009/12/07/the-importance-of-computer-silence/</guid>
      <description>It’s been a while since I’ve sincerely blogged, as I’ve been somewhat obscured by computing lately. You’d think with all these computers around me, I’d be blogging all the time; but what I really want is less of them around me so that it feels like something more special than just another thing I do on the computer.
For example, this weekend was my birthday weekend (born in 1971, for those counting), and it felt very good going on “computer silence” for two days after the Friday night party.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>i don’t know how to do anything</title>
      <link>https://sounding.com/2009/03/02/i-dont-know-how-to-do-anything/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 02 Mar 2009 17:47:32 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://sounding.com/2009/03/02/i-dont-know-how-to-do-anything/</guid>
      <description>at times i get overwhelmed by possibilities. the details drag me down, and i lose sight of the path. what causes this?
for instance, what music do i choose to write? do i use electro-acoustic elements, or do i stick to raw sound design? do these ways of working always produce the same results, even though i cannot hear them? do i limit myself by focusing on a working method that could easily shift into tunnelvision?</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>