<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>releases on Sounding</title>
    <link>https://sounding.com/tags/releases/</link>
    <description>Recent content in releases on Sounding</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Fri, 03 Jul 2009 00:33:17 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://sounding.com/tags/releases/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Appearing in variety…</title>
      <link>https://sounding.com/2009/07/02/appearing-in-variety/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 03 Jul 2009 00:33:17 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://sounding.com/2009/07/02/appearing-in-variety/</guid>
      <description>Audiobulb has released a free sampler of music from eight artists on the label, including a track off Supple (see post below), subtly arranged and expertly mixed by label owner David Newman. Others included are: Jimmy Behan, Biosphere, Ultre, NQ, Mark Harris, Hans van Eck and He Can Jog. I’m honored to be among the talent in that lineup, and the music is just awesome.
Also recently, Xynthetic produced their Second Statement, a stunning cross-section of the artist roster that displays the wide variety to be had on the netlabel.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>“Supple” out now on Audiobulb</title>
      <link>https://sounding.com/2009/04/07/supple-out-now-on-audiobulb/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 08 Apr 2009 02:45:35 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://sounding.com/2009/04/07/supple-out-now-on-audiobulb/</guid>
      <description>Presenting: an electro-acoustic album of experimental sound sources and improvisations punctuated by iterative percussion, i.e. glitchy ambient slightly funky dance music. 😉
Supple is the way I’ve seen things come together over several years after moving to California, and owes some to dance forms that made this area of the country so important to electronic music development and culture. They are presented in a sort of story-form (I’ll blame my operatic tendencies for that), where endings and beginnings aren’t so easily discerned, and overall structure blends them in a sort of high-contrast, watercolor way… which I think is matched in visual form by gl0tch (check out the release page to see different versions of the cover art morphing), giving it all this primordial evolutionary cybernetic aspect that I love, as if everything is a petri dish of mechanically chaotic musical questions.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>My best 24 hours of music in 2008</title>
      <link>https://sounding.com/2009/01/05/my-best-24-hours-of-music-in-2008/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 06 Jan 2009 05:54:52 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://sounding.com/2009/01/05/my-best-24-hours-of-music-in-2008/</guid>
      <description>I like to make myself feel as if I’m somehow close to the elusive community of electronic music. My problem, however, is that I am way too interested in multiple facets of music releases to pay attention in any style for very long. I seek out what really turns my ear, the gems of sound that are unique statements of purpose or individuality. Since I desire great pieces of listening, I spend time searching for it, which means I listen to a lot of not so great things too, and that goes double for netlabels.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Coming soon… Craque on Audiobulb</title>
      <link>https://sounding.com/2008/12/17/coming-soon-craque-on-audiobulb/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 18 Dec 2008 02:17:53 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://sounding.com/2008/12/17/coming-soon-craque-on-audiobulb/</guid>
      <description>So my new full-length album, Supple, will be released by Audiobulb in March of 2009. Ain’t that awesome! It’s a real honor to be joining in the ranks of Autistici, HeCanJog, Ultre, Calika, and so many others.
Months have gone by (actually, no, YEARS) where I have absorbed things, seen new parts of the world, learned new techniques, sought out what’s further; and this album evolved alongside me. The entire work has grown from single tracks and loose groupings to continuity and connection through thematic reverberation, it’s been fun and full of discovery.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Craque: Gamma out now on Test Tube</title>
      <link>https://sounding.com/2008/11/04/craque-gamma-out-now-on-test-tube/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 04 Nov 2008 19:37:23 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://sounding.com/2008/11/04/craque-gamma-out-now-on-test-tube/</guid>
      <description>October brought many exciting things for me, including not only a new job, but also a new album that I’m very excited about. The Test Tube netlabel is featuring this new release, called Gamma.
Six tracks, mostly beat-driven, of downtempo styled expressionism ripe with electro-acoustic improvisation; acousmatica for the brainwaves.
I was also honored to have Matt Mercer (of Microfilm) write up the release on Under the Lens, here’s an excerpt from the full article:</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Infinite Jest Project @ .microsound</title>
      <link>https://sounding.com/2008/10/14/infinite-jest-project-microsound/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 14 Oct 2008 18:14:40 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://sounding.com/2008/10/14/infinite-jest-project-microsound/</guid>
      <description>The .microsound community recently embarked on a new project to honor the life of writer David Foster Wallace, known widely for his intelligently sprawling novel Infinite Jest.
Instructions were to take one of the films attributed to the protagonist’s father and create a soundtrack. I was attracted to the surrealism in the description of Baby Pictures of Famous Dictators and almost immediately had an image of what the film would be like.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Craque: “Tekuchesti” out now on Constanta</title>
      <link>https://sounding.com/2008/10/03/craque-tekuchesti-out-now-on-the-constanta-netlabel/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 03 Oct 2008 17:55:59 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://sounding.com/2008/10/03/craque-tekuchesti-out-now-on-the-constanta-netlabel/</guid>
      <description>I’m very happy to announce the release of a project I did this summer called Tekuchesti (a transliteration of текучести, which is a Russian word meaning “fluidity”), a piece in shuffle time for listeners and improvisers.
Download the entire work, and remember to listen on shuffle. Weird request you say? Read the liner notes below for more detail…
Please also visit the release page at Constanta and check out the other artists on this new boutique netlabel, which features some unique approaches to the microsound/glitch/experimental/drone genres; beauty through subtlety and simplicity.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Craque: “Trolling for Olives” now free download</title>
      <link>https://sounding.com/2008/10/02/craque-trolling-for-olives-now-free-download/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 03 Oct 2008 01:54:44 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://sounding.com/2008/10/02/craque-trolling-for-olives-now-free-download/</guid>
      <description>In 2001 the debut 12″ for Craque titled Trolling for Olives EP was released on Metatron Press, and now it’s available for free on last.fm.
All five tracks are both streamable and downloadable, I figured I’d do them all since the original is still available for purchase on vinyl and it’s got some dope tracks!
And I don’t know how many of my fans actually read this, but here’s the first hint that you can expect several new releases coming up in the coming months.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>New Release: Material</title>
      <link>https://sounding.com/2008/07/09/new-release-material/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 09 Jul 2008 22:12:20 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://sounding.com/2008/07/09/new-release-material/</guid>
      <description>Since this release came out while my blog was unavailable, thought I would shout it out that a new Craque album called Material is available on Kahvi Collective! From the website:
 “Guest artist craque arrives on Kahvi Collective with a unique blend of textures and IDM elements. Five track ‘Material’ verges on the style of ‘MigloJE’. Torus Europa sets the scene with its lush, drawn out passages of sound and textures and leads into the interesting ‘strawberry jam’, an atonal melody drawing on a paced bass line which makes a nice combination and the extraordinary ‘organum’ (my personal favourite of this release) with ‘that’ sample hook that fits so well with the rest of the track.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Craque DJ set: Stop Time CD release party</title>
      <link>https://sounding.com/2008/05/23/craque-dj-set-stop-time-cd-release-party/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 23 May 2008 17:20:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://sounding.com/2008/05/23/craque-dj-set-stop-time-cd-release-party/</guid>
      <description>Wednesday night I played after John Harrington’s Stop Time for their CD release party, you can hear the 2-hour set new on CraqueCast or download the full thing directly.
I also have several pictures from the gig for all to see… John moves ALL THE TIME so my little digital camera could never get a clean shot of him!
As many of you may know, I improvise all my DJ sets.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>New Releases on Metatron: Joe Zitt, GWME</title>
      <link>https://sounding.com/2008/05/16/new-releases-on-metatron-joe-zitt-gwme/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 16 May 2008 17:57:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://sounding.com/2008/05/16/new-releases-on-metatron-joe-zitt-gwme/</guid>
      <description>Metatron Press has re-released a few more recordings on archive.org:
  Collaborations features Joseph Zitt’s vocals and improvisations with such musicians as F. Vattel Cherry, members of Gray Code, and an electronica treatment by Craque.
  Gusty Winds May Exist consists of Comma member Tom Bickley on recorders and electronics with Nancy Beckman on shakuhachi. This is the first in a series of three releases by each member of Comma with hand-made packaging and album design by Joe Zitt.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>T Spigot is rearing its burroughsian head once again</title>
      <link>https://sounding.com/2008/05/14/t-spigot-is-rearing-its-burroughsian-head-once-again/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 14 May 2008 18:31:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://sounding.com/2008/05/14/t-spigot-is-rearing-its-burroughsian-head-once-again/</guid>
      <description>My favorite live downtempo band – T Spigot – is back in action this year, and to start it off they’re offering the limited edition first pressing of Experiments in the Hypnotic Production of Crime, available through paypal for a measly $5, so go get it!
The bonus is that this version of the album includes the remix of dubnbud which they did for the 12″ release of Trolling for Olives.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>New Release: Density Operator</title>
      <link>https://sounding.com/2008/01/20/new-release-density-operator/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 21 Jan 2008 06:09:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://sounding.com/2008/01/20/new-release-density-operator/</guid>
      <description>Behold the appalling beautiful world of Density Operator now available on Stadtgruen.
“The title is program: everything in this world seems to be under pressure in order to extract the highest concentration of agility. Computer sounds are algorithms, just another form of mathematical strings. Thus the densification of sound works by finding the shortest possible expression.”
Music on this album picked its own paths and themes as it emerged from ideas I’ve had about quantum mechanics and atomic theory, and how the same conceptual mindspace is occupied by the intense spontaneity of improvisation.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>