<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>john cage on Sounding</title>
    <link>https://sounding.com/tags/john-cage/</link>
    <description>Recent content in john cage on Sounding</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sat, 23 Feb 2019 06:47:26 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://sounding.com/tags/john-cage/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Weirdness of Experiment</title>
      <link>https://sounding.com/2019/02/22/weirdness-of-experiment/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 23 Feb 2019 06:47:26 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://sounding.com/2019/02/22/weirdness-of-experiment/</guid>
      <description>My job in ops has always been to keep things running. I never considered myself “working in software”, but have recently begun embracing the fact that I do. What I accomplish as an operations and infrastructure engineer is part of the system, it isn’t dislocated from its composition.
Relatedly, I have been considering the nature of the experiment in Chaos Engineering. How continuous verification is becoming a crucial part of the complex systems we build because there really is no end.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Living 4’33”</title>
      <link>https://sounding.com/2019/01/19/living-433/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 19 Jan 2019 08:10:42 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://sounding.com/2019/01/19/living-433/</guid>
      <description>I haven’t experienced Mute’s STUMM433 release yet, it’s not due out until May. The proceeds from its sale go to charities, so that’s a big huge plus for it already. Pulling big names like Depeche Mode and Moby will hopefully make for good sales.
This is also not the first time 4’33” has been “recorded” for the purpose of a record release and not as part of a live performance. Frank Zappa has done it, Pauline Oliveros and the Deep Listening Band plus others, and some even got sued for it.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Ubuweb posts Greenaway’s 4 American Composers</title>
      <link>https://sounding.com/2011/12/08/ubuweb-posts-greenaways-4-american-composers/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 08 Dec 2011 16:40:26 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://sounding.com/2011/12/08/ubuweb-posts-greenaways-4-american-composers/</guid>
      <description>Back in the mid 90’s before I ever got into techno music, I owned the original VHS copy of Peter Greenaway’s 1983 release 4merican Composers (natch, “Four American Composers”) and watched it constantly while in music school; I think I probably saw the Cage movie no less than 10 times.
As a honorable musicologist is want to do, I lent my copy out to a friend who had never heard of any of them, but then never got it back because of moving across the country.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>