<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>listening on Sounding</title>
    <link>https://sounding.com/tags/listening/</link>
    <description>Recent content in listening on Sounding</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 27 Dec 2018 02:57:40 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://sounding.com/tags/listening/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Musical Intuition meet Technology and Chaos</title>
      <link>https://sounding.com/2018/12/26/musical-intuition-meet-technology-and-chaos/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 27 Dec 2018 02:57:40 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://sounding.com/2018/12/26/musical-intuition-meet-technology-and-chaos/</guid>
      <description>Today I read through the InfoQ eMag on Chaos Engineering, and was struck by John Allspaw’s (@allspaw) contribution because it reminded me of something I jotted down on a sticky at my desk a few days ago:
 Intuition is valid because it is learned like jazz changes.  I’m pretty stubborn and refuse to accept that music is merely a hobby of mine. When people ask me if electronic music or singing is my “hobby”, I am wincing inside.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Listening in 2011</title>
      <link>https://sounding.com/2012/01/11/listening-in-2011/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 11 Jan 2012 08:29:03 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://sounding.com/2012/01/11/listening-in-2011/</guid>
      <description>Three years ago was the last time I did any kind of “year’s review” of aural nourishment, and I sort of feel the need to do it again. Those 24 hours of music are worth revisiting, and the following may not even count as a “best of,” but it is some of the best music I’ve heard this year, and I listen to an awful lot. Maybe call it a “compendium”?</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Downtempo from the Studio</title>
      <link>https://sounding.com/2009/03/17/downtempo-from-the-studio/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 17 Mar 2009 21:45:15 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://sounding.com/2009/03/17/downtempo-from-the-studio/</guid>
      <description>I’ve set up a set in Soundcloud called “Downtempo Excursions” to post some sonic paintings created with free improvisation and minimal beats.
 Let me know what you think! These are sort of what I’d call “composting” of materials, kaleidoscopically tapestristic, experimentally structured.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The quake song</title>
      <link>https://sounding.com/2008/07/29/the-quake-song/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 30 Jul 2008 03:09:13 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://sounding.com/2008/07/29/the-quake-song/</guid>
      <description>Having moved to the LA area little over five years ago, it wasn’t until today that I experienced a significantly violent earthquake in our hometown of Fullerton – just across the freeway from the epicenter of the 5.4 quake in Chino Hills today.
I was talking on the phone in my studio for work, when suddenly it all started moving.
What’s interesting to me now is that though I remember the specific feeling of the earthquake, the adrenaline rush of anticipating when it will end, the cycles of disbelief and acceptance and small notions of what the edge of panic feels like… of all this, I remember the sounds the most.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>