<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>netlabels on Sounding</title>
    <link>https://sounding.com/tags/netlabels/</link>
    <description>Recent content in netlabels on Sounding</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Fri, 03 Jul 2009 00:33:17 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://sounding.com/tags/netlabels/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Appearing in variety…</title>
      <link>https://sounding.com/2009/07/02/appearing-in-variety/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 03 Jul 2009 00:33:17 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://sounding.com/2009/07/02/appearing-in-variety/</guid>
      <description>Audiobulb has released a free sampler of music from eight artists on the label, including a track off Supple (see post below), subtly arranged and expertly mixed by label owner David Newman. Others included are: Jimmy Behan, Biosphere, Ultre, NQ, Mark Harris, Hans van Eck and He Can Jog. I’m honored to be among the talent in that lineup, and the music is just awesome.
Also recently, Xynthetic produced their Second Statement, a stunning cross-section of the artist roster that displays the wide variety to be had on the netlabel.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Craque: Gamma out now on Test Tube</title>
      <link>https://sounding.com/2008/11/04/craque-gamma-out-now-on-test-tube/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 04 Nov 2008 19:37:23 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://sounding.com/2008/11/04/craque-gamma-out-now-on-test-tube/</guid>
      <description>October brought many exciting things for me, including not only a new job, but also a new album that I’m very excited about. The Test Tube netlabel is featuring this new release, called Gamma.
Six tracks, mostly beat-driven, of downtempo styled expressionism ripe with electro-acoustic improvisation; acousmatica for the brainwaves.
I was also honored to have Matt Mercer (of Microfilm) write up the release on Under the Lens, here’s an excerpt from the full article:</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Craque: “Tekuchesti” out now on Constanta</title>
      <link>https://sounding.com/2008/10/03/craque-tekuchesti-out-now-on-the-constanta-netlabel/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 03 Oct 2008 17:55:59 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://sounding.com/2008/10/03/craque-tekuchesti-out-now-on-the-constanta-netlabel/</guid>
      <description>I’m very happy to announce the release of a project I did this summer called Tekuchesti (a transliteration of текучести, which is a Russian word meaning “fluidity”), a piece in shuffle time for listeners and improvisers.
Download the entire work, and remember to listen on shuffle. Weird request you say? Read the liner notes below for more detail…
Please also visit the release page at Constanta and check out the other artists on this new boutique netlabel, which features some unique approaches to the microsound/glitch/experimental/drone genres; beauty through subtlety and simplicity.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>New Release: Material</title>
      <link>https://sounding.com/2008/07/09/new-release-material/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 09 Jul 2008 22:12:20 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://sounding.com/2008/07/09/new-release-material/</guid>
      <description>Since this release came out while my blog was unavailable, thought I would shout it out that a new Craque album called Material is available on Kahvi Collective! From the website:
 “Guest artist craque arrives on Kahvi Collective with a unique blend of textures and IDM elements. Five track ‘Material’ verges on the style of ‘MigloJE’. Torus Europa sets the scene with its lush, drawn out passages of sound and textures and leads into the interesting ‘strawberry jam’, an atonal melody drawing on a paced bass line which makes a nice combination and the extraordinary ‘organum’ (my personal favourite of this release) with ‘that’ sample hook that fits so well with the rest of the track.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>New Releases on Metatron: Joe Zitt, GWME</title>
      <link>https://sounding.com/2008/05/16/new-releases-on-metatron-joe-zitt-gwme/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 16 May 2008 17:57:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://sounding.com/2008/05/16/new-releases-on-metatron-joe-zitt-gwme/</guid>
      <description>Metatron Press has re-released a few more recordings on archive.org:
  Collaborations features Joseph Zitt’s vocals and improvisations with such musicians as F. Vattel Cherry, members of Gray Code, and an electronica treatment by Craque.
  Gusty Winds May Exist consists of Comma member Tom Bickley on recorders and electronics with Nancy Beckman on shakuhachi. This is the first in a series of three releases by each member of Comma with hand-made packaging and album design by Joe Zitt.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>New Release: Density Operator</title>
      <link>https://sounding.com/2008/01/20/new-release-density-operator/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 21 Jan 2008 06:09:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://sounding.com/2008/01/20/new-release-density-operator/</guid>
      <description>Behold the appalling beautiful world of Density Operator now available on Stadtgruen.
“The title is program: everything in this world seems to be under pressure in order to extract the highest concentration of agility. Computer sounds are algorithms, just another form of mathematical strings. Thus the densification of sound works by finding the shortest possible expression.”
Music on this album picked its own paths and themes as it emerged from ideas I’ve had about quantum mechanics and atomic theory, and how the same conceptual mindspace is occupied by the intense spontaneity of improvisation.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>