<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>glitch on Sounding</title>
    <link>https://sounding.com/tags/glitch/</link>
    <description>Recent content in glitch on Sounding</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 23 Jun 2011 06:52:13 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://sounding.com/tags/glitch/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>“Booglitchoo” Synth Prototype</title>
      <link>https://sounding.com/2011/06/22/booglitchoo-synth-prototype/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 23 Jun 2011 06:52:13 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://sounding.com/2011/06/22/booglitchoo-synth-prototype/</guid>
      <description>Here we go… I’ve optimized the way I’m using power, love the way the dual jfet opamps (TL082) sound, and have the mixing elements mostly decided.
To be done on this prototype:
 use either capacitor switching or a simple 4017 sequencer to change up the textural possibilities of the oscillator add switches to the voice modulator to allow for “skipping around” pitches instead of only up or down changes CV input  I went through quite a few opamps before finally deciding on the dual jfets, and now I really dig how they’re working with the complex waveform of the four NAND gates (NTE4093)… I use it first as a multipole low-pass filter to shape the sound of the chained oscillators.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>New improvisations on SoundCloud</title>
      <link>https://sounding.com/2009/02/21/new-improvisations-on-soundcloud/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 21 Feb 2009 19:10:57 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://sounding.com/2009/02/21/new-improvisations-on-soundcloud/</guid>
      <description>Freely improvised one-takes. Instrumentation includes homebuilt instruments, sampled objects and looping hardware.
 This music sharing site is a great tool for posting various non-published tracks, as well as released stuff, and has a nice embeddable player and comment system. Really nice for being able to just slap some stuff up, I have one friend who has recently been doing the same with sessions on his new Serge Modular Creature, and another who posted “in progress” snapshots of a track he is working on.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>DataCent Failed HD Sound Library</title>
      <link>https://sounding.com/2008/11/17/datacent-failed-hd-sound-library/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 17 Nov 2008 21:23:19 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://sounding.com/2008/11/17/datacent-failed-hd-sound-library/</guid>
      <description>Check this out… DataCent, a data recovery company, has started a catalog of common sounds heard on failing hard drives, and it covers multiple vendors and situations where things can be heard going terribly wrong. Best of all, they give full permission to use the samples as long as you contact them about it.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>