<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>labels on Sounding</title>
    <link>https://sounding.com/tags/labels/</link>
    <description>Recent content in labels on Sounding</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 11 Jan 2012 08:29:03 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://sounding.com/tags/labels/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Listening in 2011</title>
      <link>https://sounding.com/2012/01/11/listening-in-2011/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 11 Jan 2012 08:29:03 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://sounding.com/2012/01/11/listening-in-2011/</guid>
      <description>Three years ago was the last time I did any kind of “year’s review” of aural nourishment, and I sort of feel the need to do it again. Those 24 hours of music are worth revisiting, and the following may not even count as a “best of,” but it is some of the best music I’ve heard this year, and I listen to an awful lot. Maybe call it a “compendium”?</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Erotus Records Kickoff Set</title>
      <link>https://sounding.com/2008/07/29/erotus-records-kickoff-set/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 29 Jul 2008 23:34:56 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://sounding.com/2008/07/29/erotus-records-kickoff-set/</guid>
      <description>Here’s a live set from the guys at Erotus (Blamstrain’s new label) celebrating its launch, featured in the Viides Uuden Musiikin Festivaali, or “Fifth Festival for New Music”, held in Kupittaanpuisto, Turku, Finland.
Download it to hear area, asketix, blamstrain, ercola, and mk10 (not necessarily in that order) throw down a continuous two and a half hour set of glitch-filled, sometimes psychedelic, always atmospheric minimal techno from 25 July in Finland.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Twisted Records now has downloads</title>
      <link>https://sounding.com/2008/07/26/twisted-records-now-has-downloads/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 26 Jul 2008 20:04:12 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://sounding.com/2008/07/26/twisted-records-now-has-downloads/</guid>
      <description>One of my favorite sources for anything psychedelic, Twisted Records has started an online store with digital downloads.
Traditionally this has been a “DJ’s label” selling mostly vinyl and CDs of primarily music meant to be spun at a party, but it’s interesting to see them offering things digitally.
It matches up a bit with the direction of some of the music Posford and friends make now, a lot less “fringey” I’d call it – more use of pop elements some might say – not any less worldly but a lot more accessible for the common ear.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>