<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Craque on Sounding</title>
    <link>https://sounding.com/categories/craque/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Craque on Sounding</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 28 Aug 2019 22:17:02 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://sounding.com/categories/craque/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Music for WorkCats</title>
      <link>https://sounding.com/2019/08/28/music-for-workcats/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 28 Aug 2019 22:17:02 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://sounding.com/2019/08/28/music-for-workcats/</guid>
      <description>I have a few Slacks (as in chats, not pants) with #music and #jams channels where I feel obligated to post music I find good. I love sharing music. It’s why I got involved and loved my years on WUVT and WMUC DJ’ing, why I have always had a side-‘job’ as a DJ, why I made mixtapes in high school and recordings of my sets to share.
This was going to be a tweet thread but turned into something longer.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>DIY Audio: UNPLUGGED</title>
      <link>https://sounding.com/2012/04/11/diy-audio-unplugged/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 12 Apr 2012 00:36:58 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://sounding.com/2012/04/11/diy-audio-unplugged/</guid>
      <description>Probably around five years ago now, while much further in the depths of a thrice-laid-off financial hole the technology industry bestowed upon me, I became fixated with actually building my own electronic instruments. Ensuing the expertise to make music that way, I departed into the wide unknown universe of DIY audio.
The first time I encountered a small, personal modular synthesizer was during a long gallery installation and collaborative work by Achim Wollscheid in Chicago (I also happened to have given him a ride to where he was going his first night there, and had rich conversations for the short time we were all together).</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Fullerton Art Walk Menagerie</title>
      <link>https://sounding.com/2012/04/08/fullerton-art-walk-menagerie/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 09 Apr 2012 01:00:57 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://sounding.com/2012/04/08/fullerton-art-walk-menagerie/</guid>
      <description>Here’s my own collection of aural glass animals for you to enjoy… a mix of groovy and beaty dreamscapes (3:38 @ 256K cbr mp3), recorded live for the Fullerton Art Walk on Friday (April 6), accompanying tattoo artist Jon Kelly (known for Olde Tyme Tattoo) as he applies his latest in biomechanical fashion.
=== e d i t ===
…by the way a vinyl mix…
 </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>120 Hours For John Cage</title>
      <link>https://sounding.com/2012/02/14/120-hours-for-john-cage/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 14 Feb 2012 22:55:58 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://sounding.com/2012/02/14/120-hours-for-john-cage/</guid>
      <description>As you may or may not know, 2012 is the Centennial of John Cage’s birth, and among its many celebrants (including myself, details to come…) is “transmission arts” collective Free103point9, who work in conjunction with WGXC 90.7-FM in upstate New York to present works specifically designed for air-borne electro-magnetic transmission – Radio, that is.
As you also may or may not know, John Cage wrote an abundance of pieces that called for either radios as instruments or as the listening medium (i.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>SoundWalk 2011 is coming</title>
      <link>https://sounding.com/2011/08/31/soundwalk-2011-is-coming/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 31 Aug 2011 18:01:36 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://sounding.com/2011/08/31/soundwalk-2011-is-coming/</guid>
      <description>Just in case you missed it, SoundWalk Long Beach 2011 is just around the corner! Check out the newly posted set of mp3’s from last year’s event at craque.net (or download a zip file of flac files directly).
Here’s a couple of pix from last year’s event…
[][2]Craque performing at SoundWalk 2010 in Long Beach, CA [][3]Dave doubles as stagehand and soundmaker improvisor [][4]Later in the evening, up close with participants </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>“Booglitchoo” Synth Prototype</title>
      <link>https://sounding.com/2011/06/22/booglitchoo-synth-prototype/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 23 Jun 2011 06:52:13 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://sounding.com/2011/06/22/booglitchoo-synth-prototype/</guid>
      <description>Here we go… I’ve optimized the way I’m using power, love the way the dual jfet opamps (TL082) sound, and have the mixing elements mostly decided.
To be done on this prototype:
 use either capacitor switching or a simple 4017 sequencer to change up the textural possibilities of the oscillator add switches to the voice modulator to allow for “skipping around” pitches instead of only up or down changes CV input  I went through quite a few opamps before finally deciding on the dual jfets, and now I really dig how they’re working with the complex waveform of the four NAND gates (NTE4093)… I use it first as a multipole low-pass filter to shape the sound of the chained oscillators.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Why am I silent?</title>
      <link>https://sounding.com/2010/11/09/why-am-i-silent/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 10 Nov 2010 05:46:53 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://sounding.com/2010/11/09/why-am-i-silent/</guid>
      <description>Incredibly, when I was a young boy I assumed everyone was supposed to know everything. It wasn’t until I was probably 30 that I realized things are meant to be learned and practiced, never known outright or assumed to be perfect.
But I spent a long time growing up thinking the opposite, that because I didn’t know something meant I couldn’t belong.
When I was thirteen, between finishing The Lord of the Rings and discovering Playboy, I locked onto a character in David Eddings’s The Belgariad; a wizardly type bloke who espoused silence and the ability to listen, leaving speech to those who knew not how to think.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Halloween Mixes by DJ Craque</title>
      <link>https://sounding.com/2010/11/04/halloween-mixes-by-dj-craque/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 05 Nov 2010 06:03:43 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://sounding.com/2010/11/04/halloween-mixes-by-dj-craque/</guid>
      <description>This past weekend we presented ourselves in regalia of the zombie, partying until the early single digits at my good friend Chad’s.
I have played music at his Halloween parties for as long as I’ve lived in California, down in Newport Beach as well as Fullerton. In 2010 the digital world has provided us with methods of being the DJ while joining the party; what follows are the set lists I prepared for the costume extravaganza at Chad’s, each on its separate ipod in different themed rooms:</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Appearing in variety…</title>
      <link>https://sounding.com/2009/07/02/appearing-in-variety/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 03 Jul 2009 00:33:17 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://sounding.com/2009/07/02/appearing-in-variety/</guid>
      <description>Audiobulb has released a free sampler of music from eight artists on the label, including a track off Supple (see post below), subtly arranged and expertly mixed by label owner David Newman. Others included are: Jimmy Behan, Biosphere, Ultre, NQ, Mark Harris, Hans van Eck and He Can Jog. I’m honored to be among the talent in that lineup, and the music is just awesome.
Also recently, Xynthetic produced their Second Statement, a stunning cross-section of the artist roster that displays the wide variety to be had on the netlabel.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>“Supple” out now on Audiobulb</title>
      <link>https://sounding.com/2009/04/07/supple-out-now-on-audiobulb/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 08 Apr 2009 02:45:35 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://sounding.com/2009/04/07/supple-out-now-on-audiobulb/</guid>
      <description>Presenting: an electro-acoustic album of experimental sound sources and improvisations punctuated by iterative percussion, i.e. glitchy ambient slightly funky dance music. 😉
Supple is the way I’ve seen things come together over several years after moving to California, and owes some to dance forms that made this area of the country so important to electronic music development and culture. They are presented in a sort of story-form (I’ll blame my operatic tendencies for that), where endings and beginnings aren’t so easily discerned, and overall structure blends them in a sort of high-contrast, watercolor way… which I think is matched in visual form by gl0tch (check out the release page to see different versions of the cover art morphing), giving it all this primordial evolutionary cybernetic aspect that I love, as if everything is a petri dish of mechanically chaotic musical questions.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Downtempo from the Studio</title>
      <link>https://sounding.com/2009/03/17/downtempo-from-the-studio/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 17 Mar 2009 21:45:15 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://sounding.com/2009/03/17/downtempo-from-the-studio/</guid>
      <description>I’ve set up a set in Soundcloud called “Downtempo Excursions” to post some sonic paintings created with free improvisation and minimal beats.
 Let me know what you think! These are sort of what I’d call “composting” of materials, kaleidoscopically tapestristic, experimentally structured.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>My synth project: complete!</title>
      <link>https://sounding.com/2009/03/11/my-synth-project-complete/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 12 Mar 2009 07:01:29 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://sounding.com/2009/03/11/my-synth-project-complete/</guid>
      <description>Here’s something I thought I’d never see myself do in my own lifetime: build a synthesizer from scratch.
Actually it’s a simple design: 2 555 timers in astable configuration producing square-waves. This means it’s a burst of sound every interval, pretty annoying and not very useful except for maybe starting earthquakes. So to give it a little flavor, I put a low-pass, 2-pole filter on the output of each oscillator, using a traditional operational amplifier.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>i don’t know how to do anything</title>
      <link>https://sounding.com/2009/03/02/i-dont-know-how-to-do-anything/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 02 Mar 2009 17:47:32 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://sounding.com/2009/03/02/i-dont-know-how-to-do-anything/</guid>
      <description>at times i get overwhelmed by possibilities. the details drag me down, and i lose sight of the path. what causes this?
for instance, what music do i choose to write? do i use electro-acoustic elements, or do i stick to raw sound design? do these ways of working always produce the same results, even though i cannot hear them? do i limit myself by focusing on a working method that could easily shift into tunnelvision?</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>New improvisations on SoundCloud</title>
      <link>https://sounding.com/2009/02/21/new-improvisations-on-soundcloud/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 21 Feb 2009 19:10:57 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://sounding.com/2009/02/21/new-improvisations-on-soundcloud/</guid>
      <description>Freely improvised one-takes. Instrumentation includes homebuilt instruments, sampled objects and looping hardware.
 This music sharing site is a great tool for posting various non-published tracks, as well as released stuff, and has a nice embeddable player and comment system. Really nice for being able to just slap some stuff up, I have one friend who has recently been doing the same with sessions on his new Serge Modular Creature, and another who posted “in progress” snapshots of a track he is working on.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Coming soon… Craque on Audiobulb</title>
      <link>https://sounding.com/2008/12/17/coming-soon-craque-on-audiobulb/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 18 Dec 2008 02:17:53 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://sounding.com/2008/12/17/coming-soon-craque-on-audiobulb/</guid>
      <description>So my new full-length album, Supple, will be released by Audiobulb in March of 2009. Ain’t that awesome! It’s a real honor to be joining in the ranks of Autistici, HeCanJog, Ultre, Calika, and so many others.
Months have gone by (actually, no, YEARS) where I have absorbed things, seen new parts of the world, learned new techniques, sought out what’s further; and this album evolved alongside me. The entire work has grown from single tracks and loose groupings to continuity and connection through thematic reverberation, it’s been fun and full of discovery.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Craque: Gamma out now on Test Tube</title>
      <link>https://sounding.com/2008/11/04/craque-gamma-out-now-on-test-tube/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 04 Nov 2008 19:37:23 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://sounding.com/2008/11/04/craque-gamma-out-now-on-test-tube/</guid>
      <description>October brought many exciting things for me, including not only a new job, but also a new album that I’m very excited about. The Test Tube netlabel is featuring this new release, called Gamma.
Six tracks, mostly beat-driven, of downtempo styled expressionism ripe with electro-acoustic improvisation; acousmatica for the brainwaves.
I was also honored to have Matt Mercer (of Microfilm) write up the release on Under the Lens, here’s an excerpt from the full article:</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Infinite Jest Project @ .microsound</title>
      <link>https://sounding.com/2008/10/14/infinite-jest-project-microsound/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 14 Oct 2008 18:14:40 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://sounding.com/2008/10/14/infinite-jest-project-microsound/</guid>
      <description>The .microsound community recently embarked on a new project to honor the life of writer David Foster Wallace, known widely for his intelligently sprawling novel Infinite Jest.
Instructions were to take one of the films attributed to the protagonist’s father and create a soundtrack. I was attracted to the surrealism in the description of Baby Pictures of Famous Dictators and almost immediately had an image of what the film would be like.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Craque: “Tekuchesti” out now on Constanta</title>
      <link>https://sounding.com/2008/10/03/craque-tekuchesti-out-now-on-the-constanta-netlabel/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 03 Oct 2008 17:55:59 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://sounding.com/2008/10/03/craque-tekuchesti-out-now-on-the-constanta-netlabel/</guid>
      <description>I’m very happy to announce the release of a project I did this summer called Tekuchesti (a transliteration of текучести, which is a Russian word meaning “fluidity”), a piece in shuffle time for listeners and improvisers.
Download the entire work, and remember to listen on shuffle. Weird request you say? Read the liner notes below for more detail…
Please also visit the release page at Constanta and check out the other artists on this new boutique netlabel, which features some unique approaches to the microsound/glitch/experimental/drone genres; beauty through subtlety and simplicity.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Craque: “Trolling for Olives” now free download</title>
      <link>https://sounding.com/2008/10/02/craque-trolling-for-olives-now-free-download/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 03 Oct 2008 01:54:44 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://sounding.com/2008/10/02/craque-trolling-for-olives-now-free-download/</guid>
      <description>In 2001 the debut 12″ for Craque titled Trolling for Olives EP was released on Metatron Press, and now it’s available for free on last.fm.
All five tracks are both streamable and downloadable, I figured I’d do them all since the original is still available for purchase on vinyl and it’s got some dope tracks!
And I don’t know how many of my fans actually read this, but here’s the first hint that you can expect several new releases coming up in the coming months.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>haven’t i always written techno?</title>
      <link>https://sounding.com/2008/09/02/havent-i-always-written-techno/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 02 Sep 2008 22:11:42 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://sounding.com/2008/09/02/havent-i-always-written-techno/</guid>
      <description>As the summer begins its winddown, I’ve found that I’ve been writing some interesting beat-ful music at the same time I’ve been doing completely abstract sound works. It’s fun! Each opens the doors in the other, it’s pretty interesting the way the cross-over happens, and how: even moreso these days, things are sculptural and dimensional.
For long periods of time, I feel vaguely disinterested by dance music. It’s cyclical, and it makes me wonder what my music sounds like.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Experimental Music Links</title>
      <link>https://sounding.com/2008/08/25/experimental-music-links/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 25 Aug 2008 23:07:01 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://sounding.com/2008/08/25/experimental-music-links/</guid>
      <description>I’m usually happening upon all kinds of things while I’m across the Internets for work or play, and I’ll document the more interesting and pertinent ones here on sounding.com.
I keep my own list of interesting Audio Hardware, as well as links to useful Audio Software, a lot of which centers around open source or DIY.
Check out Audio Culture for general experimental audio society.
Get Some is my list of “obtaining” art and sound across the Internet, both pay-sites and places you can get free stuff.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>New Release: Material</title>
      <link>https://sounding.com/2008/07/09/new-release-material/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 09 Jul 2008 22:12:20 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://sounding.com/2008/07/09/new-release-material/</guid>
      <description>Since this release came out while my blog was unavailable, thought I would shout it out that a new Craque album called Material is available on Kahvi Collective! From the website:
 “Guest artist craque arrives on Kahvi Collective with a unique blend of textures and IDM elements. Five track ‘Material’ verges on the style of ‘MigloJE’. Torus Europa sets the scene with its lush, drawn out passages of sound and textures and leads into the interesting ‘strawberry jam’, an atonal melody drawing on a paced bass line which makes a nice combination and the extraordinary ‘organum’ (my personal favourite of this release) with ‘that’ sample hook that fits so well with the rest of the track.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>New Release: Density Operator</title>
      <link>https://sounding.com/2008/01/20/new-release-density-operator/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 21 Jan 2008 06:09:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://sounding.com/2008/01/20/new-release-density-operator/</guid>
      <description>Behold the appalling beautiful world of Density Operator now available on Stadtgruen.
“The title is program: everything in this world seems to be under pressure in order to extract the highest concentration of agility. Computer sounds are algorithms, just another form of mathematical strings. Thus the densification of sound works by finding the shortest possible expression.”
Music on this album picked its own paths and themes as it emerged from ideas I’ve had about quantum mechanics and atomic theory, and how the same conceptual mindspace is occupied by the intense spontaneity of improvisation.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>